Indians!
The cave!
Charge!
Shit! The cavalry!
Damn, I ripped
the fuel line.
Maggie! Fetch some water!
We got a hurt man here.
Mom! Mom, is that you?
There, there now.
You've been asleep for
nearly six hours now.
I had this
horrible nightmare.
I dreamed... I dreamed
I was in a Western.
I was being chased by all
these Indians and a bear.
Well, you're safe
and sound
here now
at the McFly farm.
McFly farm?
Well, you're my...
You're my, my...
Who are you?
The name is McFly.
Maggie McFly.
McFly. Maggie?
And that's Mrs. McFly, and
don't you be forgetting the Mrs.
And what might
your name be, sir?
Well, it's...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
Well, you hit your head,
Mr. Eastwood.
Not too serious,
but lucky for you,
Seamus found you
when he did.
Seamus.
Me husband.
You'll be excusing me, Mr.
Eastwood, while I tend to William.
William.
Oh, that's okay, Will.
It's okay.
That's William?
Aye.
William Sean McFly, the first of
our family to be born in America.
It's okay, Will.
This here is Mr. Clint
Eastwood here visiting.
He surely likes you,
Mr. Eastwood.
Maggie.
I've got supper.
I'm not one to pry into
a man's personal affairs,
but exactly how is it that
you came to be way out here
without a horse,
or boots, or a hat?
Well, my car...
Horse broke down,
and a bear ate my boots,
and I guess
I just forgot my hat.
How could you forget
a thing like your hat?
Would you like
some water?
Yeah.
I'll tell you what
I'll do, Mr. Eastwood.
I'll help you find
your blacksmith friend.
You can stay
the night in the barn,
and tomorrow I'll take you
as far as the railroad tracks.
You can follow them
straight on into town.
I'll even
give you a hat.
That's great. Thanks.
Ah...
That's my William.
Oh.
Yes.
I think you'll find
the barn comfortable.
Never had any complaints
about it from the pigs.
Mmm.
Seamus!
A word with you.
Aye.
Will you hold him
for a minute?
Are you sure you're not after
bringing a curse on this house
taking him in
like that?
He's such
a strange young man.
Aye. But I've just got a
feeling about him, Maggie,
that looking after him
is the right thing to do.
That it's important.
Hey, buddy.
Look how the baby
takes to him.
Little Will never
takes to strangers.
It's almost as if
he's connected to us.
Hey, Will.
So you're my
great-grandfather.
The first McFly
born in America.
And you peed on me.
Give us some soap.
Here you go.
Take a look and see what
just breezed in the door.
Why, I didn't know
the circus was in town.
Must have got that
shirt off a dead Chinese.
What will it be,
stranger?
I'll have ice water.
Ice water?
Water?
You want water, you
better go dunk your head
in the horse trough
out there.
In here,
we pour whiskey.
Excuse me.
For what?
I'm trying to
find the blacksmith.
Hey, McFly!
Thought I done told
you never to come in...
You ain't
Seamus McFly.
You look like him,
though,
especially with
that dog-ugly hat.
You kin to
that hay barber?
What's your name,
dude?
Marty...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
What kind of
stupid name is that?
I'd say he's the runt of the litter.
Hey, now, boys, would you take a
look-see at these pearly whites?
Hell, I ain't seen
teeth look that straight
that weren't
store-bought.
Take a gander at
them moccasins.
What kind of skins
is them?
What's that
writing mean?
"Nike"?
What is that?
Some sort of Injun
talk or something?
Bartender, I'm looking for that
no-good, cheating blacksmith.
You seen him?
No, sir, Mr. Tannen.
I have not.
Tannen.
You're "Mad Dog" Tannen.
"Mad Dog"?
I hate that name.
I hate it, you hear?
Nobody calls me
"Mad Dog"!
Especially not some duded-up,
egg-sucking gutter trash.
Dance!
Come on!
Come on, runt! You can
dance better than that!
Shit.
Whoo!
You better run,
squirrel.
Get him!
Whoa!
We got ourselves
a new courthouse.
High time
we had a hanging!
Look at him swing.
Yeah, haven't had a
hanging in a long time!
It'll shoot the fleas off a
dog's back at 500 yards, Tannen,
and it's pointed
straight at your head!
You owe me money,
blacksmith.
How do you figure?
My horse threw a shoe.
And seeing as you was the
one that done the shoeing,
I say that makes
you responsible.
Well, since you never paid me for
the job, I say that makes us even.
Wrong! See I was
on my horse
when it threw the shoe,
and I got throwed off!
And that caused me
to bust a perfectly
good bottle of
fine Kentucky red eye.
So the way
I figure it, blacksmith,
you owe me $5
for the whiskey
and $75 for the horse!
That's the $80.
Look, if your horse
threw a shoe,
bring him back,
and I'll reshoe him.
I done shot that horse!
Well, that's your problem,
Tannen.
Wrong. That's yours.
So from now on, you better be
looking behind you when you walk.
Because one day you're gonna
get a bullet in your back.
Doc!
Marty, I gave you explicit
instructions not to come here
but to go
directly back to 1985.
I know, Doc,
but I had to come.
But it's good to
see you, Marty.
Marty, you're gonna have to do
something about those clothes.
You walk around town
dressed like that,
you're liable
to get shot.
Or hanged.
What idiot dressed you
in that outfit?
You did.
"Shot in the back
by Buford Tannen
"over a matter of $80,
"September 7"?
That's this Monday!
Now I wish
I'd paid him off.
And who's this
beloved Clara?
I don't know
anyone named Clara.
I don't know, Doc.
I thought maybe she was
a girlfriend of yours.
Marty, my involvement in such a
social relationship here in 1885
could result in a disruption
of the space-time continuum.
As a scientist, I can
never take that risk.
Certainly not after what
we've already been through.
Emmett!
Hello, Emmett.
Hubert.
It's the mayor.
Excuse me, Emmett.
Do you remember last week at the
town meeting when you volunteered
to meet the new
schoolteacher
at the station
when she came in?
Oh, yes, quite so.
Well, we just got word
she's coming in tomorrow.
Here are the details
for you.
Thanks for
all your help.
Anytime, Hubert.
Oh! Her name's Miss
Clayton. Clara Clayton.
Well, Doc, now we know who Clara is.
Marty, it's impossible.
The idea that I could fall in love
at first sight is romantic nonsense.
There's no scientific
rationale for that concept.
Aw, come on, Doc.
It's not science.
You meet the right girl, it just
hits you. It's like lightning.
Marty, please
don't say that.
That's the way it was
for me and Jennifer.
I mean, we couldn't keep
our eyes off each other.
God, Jennifer, damn. I
hope she's all right, Doc.
I can't believe we just
left her there on the porch.
Don't worry, Marty.
She'll be fine.
When you burned
the almanac in 1955,
the normal timeline
was restored.
That means once
we're back in 1985,
you just have to go over
to her house to wake her up.
Oh, Marty, turn that valve over there
all the way
to the right.
Yeah, pull it
all the way around.
Okay. Let's go!
Iced tea?
No, thanks.
It's a refrigerator.
Well, I guess
Miss Clayton
will have to find
other transportation.
If I never
meet the woman,
there's no possibility of a
romantic infatuation, right?
You're the doc, Doc.
All right.
We'll get the DeLorean and get
ourselves back to the future.
Oh, listen, Doc,
I tore a hole
in the gas tank
when I was landing,
so we're gonna have to
patch it up and get some gas.
You mean we're
out of gas?
Yeah, it's no big deal.
We've got
Mr. Fusion, right?
Mr. Fusion powers the time
circuits and the Flux Capacitor,
but the internal combustion
engine runs on ordinary gasoline.
It always has.
There's not gonna be
a gas station around here
until sometime in
the next century.
Without gasoline,
we can't get the DeLorean
up to 88 miles per hour.
So what do we do?
Twenty-four!
It's no use, Marty!
Even the fastest
horse in the world
won't run more than 35,
40 miles an hour!
Bartender said that's the
strongest stuff they got.
Try it, Marty.
Give it more gas!
Damn!
It blew the fuel
injection manifold.
Strong stuff,
all right.
It will take me a month
to rebuild it.
A month?
Doc, you're gonna
get shot on Monday!
I know! I know!
I know! I wish...
Wait. I've got it! We can
simply roll it down a steep hill!
Oh! We'd never find
a smooth enough surface.
Unless...
Of course! Ice!
We'll wait until winter
when the lake freezes over.
Winter? Doc, what are you talking about?
Monday!
It's three days away!
All right, all right,
all right.
Just let's think this
thing through logically.
We know it won't run
under its own power.
We know
we can't pull it.
But if we could
figure out a way
to push it up to
88 miles an hour.
Huh?
That's it.
How fast can she go? Why,
I've had her up to 55 myself.
I heard that
Fearless Frank Fargo
got one of these
up to near 70
out past
Verde Junction.
Do you think it's possible
to get it up to 90?
Ninety?
Tarnation, son, who'd ever
need to be in such a hurry?
It's just a little bet
he and I have, that's all.
Theoretically speaking,
could it be done?
Well, I suppose,
if you had a straight
stretch of track
with a level grade,
and you weren't hauling
no cars behind you,
and if you could get
the fire hot enough.
And I'm talking about hotter than the
blazes of hell and damnation itself.
Then yes, sir, it might be
possible to get her up that fast.
Tell me, when does the next
train come through here?
Monday morning at 8:00.
Here. This spur that
runs off the main line
three miles out
to Clayton Ravine.
It's a long stretch
of level track
that will still
exist in 1985.
This is where we'll push the
DeLorean with the locomotive.
Funny. This map calls
Clayton Ravine Shonash Ravine.
That must be the old Indian
name for it. It's perfect.
A nice long run
that goes clear across
the bridge
over the ravine,
you know, over near that
Hilldale housing development.
Right, Doc, but according to
this map, there is no bridge.
Well, Doc,
we can scratch that idea.
I mean, we can't
wait a year and a half
for this thing
to get finished.
Marty, it's perfect.
You're just not thinking
fourth-dimensionally.
Right. Right. I have a
real problem with that.
Don't you see? The
bridge will exist in 1985.
It's safe
and still in use.
Therefore, as long as we get the
DeLorean up to 88 miles an hour
before we hit
the edge of the ravine,
we'll instantaneously
arrive at a point in time
where the bridge
is completed.
We'll have track under us and
coast safely across the ravine.
What about
the locomotive?
It will be
a spectacular wreck.
Too bad no one will
be around to see it.
Help me! Help!
Great Scott!
Hurry!
Jump!
Whoa.
Oh...
Thank you, sir.
You saved my...
...life.
Emmett Brown at
your service, Miss...
Clayton.
Clara Clayton.
Clara!
What a beautiful name.
May I help you
inside with these?
Oh, no, that won't be
necessary. I can take care of it.
You've done more
than enough already.
But it's really
no trouble.
Doc, she says it's fine,
and we got to get going.
Ma'am, good luck with your
school teaching and everything.
Clara, I'll straighten
everything out
with Mr. Statler for
the buckboard rental.
Don't worry about that.
I feel somewhat responsible
for what happened.
Oh.
That would be very gentlemanly
of you, Mr. Brown. Emmett.
You know,
I'm almost glad
that snake
spooked those horses.
Otherwise,
we might never have met.
I suppose
it was destiny.
Well, thank you
for everything.
You're quite welcome.
I will see you again,
won't I?
Of course.
You'll see lots of me.
I'm sure.
I have a shop in town.
I'm the local scientist,
blacksmith.
Science?
What sort of science?
Astronomy?
Chemistry?
Actually, I'm a student
of all sciences.
Hey, Doc,
we got to get going.
Oh, yes.
Well, excuse us, Clara.
We have to get going.
Toodle-oo.
What do you mean, you're gonna
be seeing lots of her, Doc?
Well, I might see her
again just in passing.
Come on, Doc. Did you see the
way she was looking at you?
She did have
quite a scare, right?
After all, Miss Clayton
almost ended up
at the bottom of
Clayton Ravine.
Holy shit. Hey, Doc, Clayton
Ravine was named after a teacher.
They say she fell in
there 100 years ago.
100 years ago!
That's this year!
Every kid in school
knows that story,
'cause we all
have teachers
we'd like to see
fall into the ravine.
Great Scott!
Then she was supposed
to go over in that wagon.
Now I may have
seriously altered history.
Look, Doc, what's the
worst that can happen, huh?
So they don't name
the ravine after her.
Let's just get
the DeLorean ready
and get the hell
out of here.
I wish I'd never invented
that infernal time machine.
It's caused
nothing but disaster.
Doc, Doc,
this is Marty.
Do you read me? Over.
Check, Marty.
Great, Doc.
These things still work.
All right, Marty.
Once more, let's go over
the entire plan and layout.
I apologize for the crudity
of this model, but I just...
Yeah, I know, Doc. It's not
to scale. It's okay, Doc.
All right.
Tomorrow night, Sunday,
we'll load the DeLorean onto
the tracks here, on the spur
right by the old
abandoned silver mine.
The switch track is where the
spur runs off the main line
three miles out to
Clayton... Shonash Ravine.
The train leaves the station
at 8:00 Monday morning.
We'll stop it here, uncouple
the cars from the tender,
throw the switch track,
and then we'll hijack...
Borrow the locomotive and use
it to push the time machine.
According to
my calculations,
we'll reach
88 miles per hour
just before we hit
the edge of the ravine,
at which point we'll be
instantaneously transported back to 1985
and coast safely across
the completed bridge.
What does this mean?
"Point of no return. "
That's our
fail-safe point.
Up until there, we have
still have enough time
to stop the locomotive before
it plunges into the ravine.
But once we
pass this windmill,
it's the future
or bust.
Here you go, Marty. Connect
that to the positive terminal.
All right,
Marty, you all set?
Yeah. Yeah. Go!
Train pulling
out of the station!
Coming up to
the switch track!
Stop at
Throw the switch!
Pull up
to the DeLorean!
Pushing the DeLorean
up to 88 miles per hour!
It couldn't be simpler.
Emmett?
It's Clara.
Quick,
cover the DeLorean!
Hello.
Why, hello.
This is
quite a surprise.
Well, I hope I'm not
disturbing anything.
Oh, no, no, we were just doing
a little model railroading.
Oh.
Emmett, when my bags were
thrown from the wagon,
my telescope
was damaged.
And since you mentioned
an interest in science,
I thought you might be
able to repair it for me.
I would pay you,
of course.
Oh, no, no, no. I wouldn't
think of charging you for this.
Well, let's have
a look at it.
I think a lens may
be out of alignment,
because if you
move it this way,
the image turns fuzzy.
See?
But if you turn it
the other way then...
Everything becomes...
...clear.
I could repair it right away
and have it for you tonight.
Oh, tonight is
the town festival.
I wouldn't dream of having
you work on my telescope
during such
an important occasion.
You are planning on
attending, aren't you?
Well, actually,
ma'am, I don't think...
Yes, of course,
the festival.
Well, in that case,
I'll see you this evening
at the festival, Emmett.
Mr. Eastwood.
Ma'am.
Thank you for taking
care of my telescope.
You're quite welcome.
It's a nice telescope.
Ladies and gentlemen,
as mayor of Hill Valley,
it gives me great pleasure
to dedicate this clock to
the people of Hill County!
May it stand
for all time!
Tell me when, gentlemen.
Three! Two! One!
Now!
Let the festivities
begin!
You know, Marty,
in a way, it's fitting
that you and I are
here to witness this.
It's too bad I didn't
bring my camera.
Ready, gentlemen?
The only problem is we'll never
be able to show it to anybody.
Smile, Doc.
Yee-ha!
What great music!
Yeah, it's got a beat,
and you can dance to it.
Step right up
gentlemen
and test your mettle
with the latest products
from Colonel Samuel Colt's Patent
Firearms Manufacturing Company
of Hartford,
Connecticut.
Now, take this model,
for example.
The new, improved and
refined Colt Peacemaker
selling to you tonight for
the low, low price of $12.
Good evening.
Evening.
You look very nice.
Thank you.
Would you like...
Would you care to...
I'd love to.
Young man, how about you?
You want to give it a try?
No, no. No, thanks.
Hey, Doc, this...
Son!
Sonny boy!
The Doc can dance?
Son. Son. Son!
Hey, I just told you that even
a baby could handle this weapon.
Surely you're not afraid to try
something that a baby could do.
Hey, I'm not afraid
of nothing.
Come on, then. Let's just
step up here like a man.
Now, then what you do is you
just ease that hammer back there
and squeeze off
a round.
No, no, no!
Right on out there
and be real smooth.
That's the way
you do it.
Listen,
can I try that again?
Yeah, go ahead.
Hey, just tell me
one thing.
Where did you learn
to shoot like that?
7- Eleven.
Buford, you sure
that blacksmith
is gonna be at
this here shindig?
Sure he's here.
Everybody's here tonight.
You gentlemen will have
to check your firearms
if you want to join in
on the festivities.
Who's gonna make us,
tenderfoot? You?
I am.
Marshal Strickland. I didn't
know you was back in town.
If you can't
read the sign, Tannen,
I presume
you can read this.
Pretty tough hombre
when you're pointing
a scatter gun
at a man's back.
Just like you, Tannen, I take
every advantage I can get.
Now you gonna
check your iron?
I was just joking
with your deputy.
Of course,
I'm gonna check my iron.
We all were.
Weren't we, boys?
Yeah, right.
Tannen.
Your knife, too.
Smile, Marshal. After
all, this is a party.
Only party
I'll be smiling at
is the one that sees you
at the end of a rope.
Have fun!
See, that's how
you handle them, Son.
Never give them
an inch
and maintain discipline
at all times.
Remember that word,
discipline.
I will, Pa.
Swing that partner
With a right big swing
Over to the side
It's the same old thing
Thank you very much.
Why, Mr. Eastwood,
nice to see you.
I see you got yourself some respectable
clothes, lad, and a fine hat.
Yeah, well,
a couple people
didn't like the way the
other one looked on me.
Sure, and that one
suits you, Mr. Eastwood.
It's very becoming.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, "Frisbie. "
Far out.
What was the meaning
of that?
It was right in front of him. Aye.
Swing that partner
halfway round
Sashay back to
the head of the set
All the way up to
Now, bow to the partner
You're through
Hey, that's mine!
Not anymore.
Give me that.
There he is, Buford.
Where?
There.
Dancing with that
piece of calico.
What are you
gonna do, boss?
I figure if I bury
this muzzle
deep enough in his back,
nobody will hear the shot.
Careful, Buford. You ain't
got but one bullet with that.
I only need one.
I told you to watch
your back, smithy.
Tannen, you're early.
It's a Derringer, smithy.
Small but effective.
The last time I used it, fellow
took two whole days to die.
Bled to death inside.
It was real,
real painful.
That means you'll be dead
by about supper time Monday.
Excuse me. I don't know who you
think you are, but we're dancing.
Well, look at what
we have here.
Ain't you gonna
introduce me to the lady?
I'd like a dance.
I wouldn't give
you the pleasure.
You'll just have to
go ahead and shoot.
All right.
No, no. Emmett,
I'll dance with him.
Boys, keep the
blacksmith company
while I get acquainted
with the filly!
I don't dance very well when my
partner has a gun in his hand.
You'll learn.
You know, smithy, maybe I'll
just take my $80 worth out of her!
Tannen,
leave her alone!
Whoo!
Yeah, I bet there's something
you can do that's worth $80.
I believe you've
underestimated me, mister.
Have I?
Ow!
Stop it!
Damn you, Tannen!
No, I damn you!
I damn you to hell!
You.
Hey, lighten up, jerk!
Mighty strong words,
runt!
You man enough
to back them up
with more than
just a pie plate?
Look, just leave
my friends alone.
What's wrong, dude?
You yellow?
That's what I thought.
A yellow belly.
Nobody calls me yellow.
Then let's
finish it right now.
Not now, Buford.
Marshal's got our guns.
Like I said,
we'll finish this tomorrow!
Tomorrow we're robbing
the Pine City stage.
What about Monday?
We doing anything Monday?
No, Monday would be fine.
You can kill him on Monday.
I'll be back
this way on Monday.
We'll settle this then.
Right there
out in the street
in front of
the Palace Saloon.
Yeah, right. When?
High noon?
Noon?
I do my killing
before breakfast. 7:00!
8:00. I do my killing
after breakfast.
Marty!
All right, now.
Break it up.
What's all this about?
You causing
trouble here, Tannen?
No trouble, Marshal.
Just a little personal matter
between me and Eastwood.
This don't
concern the law.
Tonight, everything concerns
the law. Now break it up.
Any brawling, it's 15
days in the county jail.
All right, folks.
Come on, this is a party.
Come on!
Let's have some fun!
8:00 Monday, runt.
If you ain't here,
I'll hunt you and shoot
you down like a duck.
It's "dog," Buford.
Shoot him down like a dog.
Let's go, boys! Let these
sissies have their party!
Marty,
what are you doing,
saying you're
gonna meet Tannen?
Hey, Doc, Doc,
don't worry about it.
Monday morning 8:00 a. m.
We're gonna
be gone, right?
Theoretically, yes, but
what if the train's late?
Late? We'll discuss this later.
No, we'll discuss it now.
Late? What do you mean?
Thank you for your
gallantry, Mr. Eastwood.
Hey, ma'am.
Had you not interceded,
Emmett might have been shot.
Marty... Clint, I'm
gonna take Clara home.
Right. Good night,
Doc. Good night, Clara.
You sure set him straight,
Mr. Eastwood.
I'm glad somebody
finally got the gumption
to stand up to
that son of a bitch.
You're all right in
my book, Mr. Eastwood.
I'd like to
buy you a drink.
Hey, listen,
I don't want a drink.
You don't have to buy me
anything. Young man. Young man.
It was no big deal. I'd like
for you to have this brand-new
Colt Peacemaker and
gun belt free of charge.
Free?
I want everybody
to know
that the gun that shot Buford
Tannen was a Colt Peacemaker!
Hey, no problem.
Thanks a lot.
Of course
you understand
that if you lose,
I'm taking it back.
Thanks again.
You had him,
Mr. Eastwood.
You could have
just walked away,
and nobody would have thought
the less of you for it.
All it would have been was
words, hot air from a buffoon.
Instead,
you let him rile you.
Rile you into playing his
game, his way, by his rules.
Seamus, relax.
I know what I'm doing.
He reminds me
of poor Martin.
Aye.
Who?
Me brother.
Wait a minute.
You have a brother
named Martin McFly?
Had a brother.
Martin used to let men
provoke him into fighting.
He was concerned that people would
think him a coward if he refused.
That's how he got a Bowie
knife shoved through his belly
in a saloon
in Virginia City.
Never considered
the future, poor Martin.
God rest his soul.
Sure, and I hope you're considering
the future, Mr. Eastwood.
I think about it
all the time.
And that crater
in the middle north west,
the one that's out there all
by itself like a starburst...
Uh-huh.
...that one's
called Copernicus.
Listen to me. I feel
like I'm teaching school.
Please,
continue the lesson.
I never found lunar
geography so fascinating.
You're quite
knowledgeable.
When I was 11,
I had diphtheria.
I was quarantined
for three months.
So my father
brought this telescope,
and he put it
next to my bed
so I could see
everything out the window.
Emmett, do you think we'll ever
be able to travel to the moon
the way we travel across
the country on trains?
Definitely. Although not for
84 years and not on trains.
We'll have space vehicles,
capsules sent aloft with rockets.
Devices that
create giant explosions.
Explosions so powerful
that they just...
That they break the pull
of the Earth's gravity
and send the projectile
through outer space.
Emmett,
I read that book, too!
You're quoting
Jules Verne
From the Earth
to the Moon.
You've read Jules Verne?
I adore Jules Verne.
So do I.
Twenty Thousand Leagues Under
the Sea. My absolute favorite.
The first time I read that
when I was a little boy,
why, I wanted to
meet Captain Nemo.
Don't tease, Emmett.
You couldn't have read
that when you were a boy.
It was only first
published 10 years ago.
Oh, yes. Well, I meant it
made me feel like a boy.
I never met a woman who
liked Jules Verne before.
I never ever met a man
like you before.
Doc?
Hope you know
what you're doing.
You talking to me?
You talking to me,
Tannen?
Well, I'm the
only one here.
Go ahead,
make my day.
Say good morning,
Mr. Eastwood.
Morning.
Have a cigar,
Mr. Eastwood.
Anything I can do for
you today, Mr. Eastwood?
No, that's fine.
Good luck tomorrow,
Mr. Eastwood.
We'll be praying
for you.
Thanks.
Good morning,
Mr. Eastwood.
Interest you in a new suit for tomorrow?
I'm fine. Thanks.
Doc, what are
you doing?
Oh, nothing.
I was just out
enjoying the morning air.
It's really lovely here in
the morning. Don't you think?
Yeah, it's lovely, Doc.
So listen, we've got
to load the DeLorean up
and get ready
to roll, all right?
Hey, look at that,
the tombstone.
Marty, let me see
that photograph again.
My name,
it's vanished.
Hey, that's great, Doc.
Don't you get it?
We're going back to
the future tomorrow,
so everything's
being erased.
But only my name
is erased.
The tombstone itself
and the date still remain.
That doesn't
make sense.
We know that this photograph
represents what will happen
if the events
of today continue
to run their course
into tomorrow.
Right. So?
Excuse me,
Mr. Eastwood.
I just need to take
your measurements.
Oh, look, pal, I don't
want to buy a suit.
No, this is
for your coffin.
My coffin?
Well, the odds are running
two to one against you.
Might as well
be prepared.
So it may not be my name that's
supposed to end up on this tombstone.
It may be yours.
Great Scott.
I know.
This is heavy.
Marty, why are you
wearing that gun?
You're not considering going
up against Tannen tomorrow?
Doc, tomorrow morning I'm going
back to the future with you.
But if Buford Tannen
comes looking for trouble,
I'm gonna be
ready for him.
You heard what that son of
a bitch called me last night.
Marty, you can't go
losing your judgment
every time someone
calls you a name.
That's exactly
what causes you
to get into that accident
in the future.
What?
What about my future?
I can't tell you. It
might make things worse.
Wait a minute. Doc, what
is wrong with my future?
Marty, we all have to make decisions
that affect
the course of our lives.
You've got to do
what you've got to do,
and I've got to do
what I've got to do.
Marty.
Yeah.
I've made a decision.
Uh-huh.
I'm not going
with you tomorrow.
I'm staying here.
What are you
talking about, Doc?
There's no point
in denying it.
I'm in love with Clara.
Oh, man.
Doc, we don't belong
here. Neither one of us.
You know, it could still be
you that gets shot tomorrow.
This tombstone could
still be in your future.
Marty, the future
isn't written.
It can be changed.
You know that.
Anyone can make their future
whatever they want it to be.
I can't let this
one little photograph
determine
my entire destiny.
I have to
live my life
according to what I believe
is right in my heart.
Doc, you're a scientist.
So you tell me. What's the
right thing to do up here?
You're right, Marty.
Wow, that worked great.
I've at least got
to tell her goodbye.
Come on, Doc.
Think about it.
What are you
gonna say to her?
"I've got to go
back to the future?"
I mean, she's not gonna
understand that, Doc.
Hell, I'm in it
with you,
and I don't
even understand it.
Doc, listen.
Maybe we...
I don't know, maybe we can
just take Clara with us.
To the future?
As you reminded me,
Marty, I'm a scientist,
so I must be
scientific about this.
I cautioned you about
disrupting the continuum
for your own
personal benefit.
Therefore,
I must do no less.
We shall proceed
as planned,
and as soon as
we return to 1985,
we'll destroy this
infernal machine.
Traveling through time has
become much too painful.
It's Emmett, Clara.
Emmett,
won't you come in?
No, I better not. I...
What's wrong?
I've come
to say goodbye.
Goodbye? Well,
where are you going?
I'm going away.
And well, I'm afraid
I'll never see you again.
Emmett!
Clara, I want you to know
that I care about you deeply.
But I've realized that
I don't belong here,
and I have to go back
where I came from.
And where
might that be?
I can't tell you.
Well, wherever you're
going, take me with you.
I can't, Clara.
I wish it didn't
have to be this way,
but just believe me
when I tell you
that I'll never forget you
and that I love you.
I don't understand what
you're trying to say.
Clara, I don't think there's any
way that you can understand it.
Please, Emmett.
Please, I have to know.
If you sincerely
do love me,
then tell me
the truth.
All right then.
I'm from the future.
I came here in a time
machine that I invented,
and tomorrow I have to
go back to the year 1985.
Yes, Emmett.
I do understand.
I understand that
because you know
I'm partial to the
writings of Jules Verne,
you concocted
those mendacities
in order to take
advantage of me.
Oh! I've heard some
whoppers in my day,
but the fact
that you'd expect me
to entertain
a notion like that
is so insulting
and degrading!
All you had to say is,
"I don't love you,
"and I don't want
to see you anymore. "
That, at least, would
have been respectful!
But that's
not the truth.
Good to
see you, too.
Emmett. What can I get you? The usual?
No, Chester, I'm gonna need something
a lot stronger
than that tonight.
Sarsaparilla.
Whiskey, Chester.
Whiskey?
Emmett, are you sure?
You know what happened to
you on the Fourth of July.
Whiskey.
Okay, I ain't your papa.
Just don't want to see
you do the wrong thing.
You can leave
the bottle.
It's a woman, right?
I knew it. I have seen
that look on a man's face
a thousand times
all across the country.
All I can tell you, friend,
is you'll get over her.
Oh... Clara was
one in a million.
One in a billion.
One in a googolplex.
The woman of my dreams, and
I've lost her for all time.
I can assure you, sir,
there are other women.
Why, peddling this barbed
wire all across the country
has taught me
one thing for certain,
is that you never know
what the future might bring.
The future. Oh, I can
tell you about the future.
Oh, man, did I sleep.
What time is it, Doc?
Doc?
Wake up!
Get up! Let's go!
I got me
a runt to kill.
It's still early, boss.
What's your hurry?
I'm hungry.
And in the future,
we don't need horses.
We have motorized carriages
called automobiles.
If everybody's got one
of these auto whatsits,
does anybody walk
or run anymore?
Of course we run, but
for recreation, for fun.
Run for fun? What the
hell kind of fun is that?
Doc! Doc!
How much
has he had?
None.
That's the first one,
and he hasn't
touched it yet.
He just likes
to hold it.
Doc! Doc!
What are you doing?
I've lost her, Marty. There's
nothing left for me here.
All right, that's why you
gotta come back with me.
Where?
Back to the future!
Right!
Let's get going!
Great.
Gentlemen, excuse me, but my
friend and I have to catch a train.
Here's to you,
blacksmith.
And to the future.
Amen.
Emmett, no!
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Come on, Doc.
Wake up. Wake up, Doc!
How many did he have?
Just the one.
Just the one?
Come on, Doc.
There's a fellow that
can't hold his liquor.
Get me some coffee.
Black!
Joey, coffee!
Ma'am?
How far does
the 8:00 train go?
San Francisco is
the end of the line.
I'll take
a one-way ticket.
You want to sober him
up in a hurry, son,
you're gonna have to use something
a lot stronger than coffee.
Yeah,
what do you suggest?
Joey, let's make
some wake-up juice.
Come on, Doc, swallow.
Here we go.
In about 10 minutes,
he's gonna be as sober
as a priest on Sunday.
Ten minutes!
Why do we have to cut
these things so damn close?
Here, stick this
clothespin on his nose.
When he opens up
his mouth,
go ahead and pour it on down his gullet.
Oh, and stand back.
He's still out!
Oh, that? That was
just a reflex action.
It's gonna take
a few more minutes
for the stuff to really
clear up his head.
Perfect.
Come on, Doc.
Come on, wake up, buddy.
Wake up, Doc!
Come on. Come on.
Seamus, wouldn't expect to
see you here this morning.
Aye. Something inside me
told me I should be here
as if my future had
something to do with it.
He'll come around
in a minute. Come on.
Come on, Doc.
Let's go, Doc!
Let's wake up now, buddy.
Come on.
Are you in there,
Eastwood?
It's 8:00,
and I'm calling you out.
It's not 8:00 yet!
It is by my watch!
Let's settle this
once and for all, runt!
Or ain't you
got the gumption?
Listen.
I'm not really feeling up to this today.
So I'm gonna
have to forfeit.
Forfeit?
What's that mean?
It means that you win
without a fight.
Without shooting?
He can't do that.
Hey, you can't do that!
You know what I think?
I think you ain't nothing
but a gutless, yellow turd!
And I'm giving you
to the count of 10
to come out here
and prove I'm wrong!
One!
Doc, come on, sober up,
buddy. Let's go. Come on.
Two!
You better get
out there, son.
I got $20 gold bet on
you, so don't let me down.
Three!
I got $30 gold bet against
you, so don't let me down.
Four!
You better face
up to it, son,
because if you
don't go out there...
What?
Five!
What if I don't
go out there?
You're a coward.
Six!
And you'll be branded a coward
for the rest of your days!
Everybody everywhere
will say Clint Eastwood
is the biggest yellow belly in the West!
Seven!
Here!
Eight!
I already got a gun.
Nine!
Ten!
Do you hear me, runt?
I said that's 10, you
gutless, yellow pie-slinger!
He's an asshole!
I don't care
what Tannen says!
And I don't care what
anybody else says either.
Doc! Doc, you okay?
I think so.
What a headache!
Listen, you got a back
door to this place?
Yeah, it's in the back.
Let's go, Doc.
Are you coming out here, or
do I have to come in after you?
The thing I really
miss here is Tylenol.
Hey!
Reach, blacksmith!
Yes, sir, that poor fellow last night
had the worst case of broken
heart I have ever seen.
When he said
he didn't know
how he could live
the rest of his life
knowing how much hurt he'd
caused that little girl.
Well, I really felt for
him. I did. Right here.
Listen up, Eastwood!
I aim to shoot
somebody today,
and I prefer
it'd be you.
But if you're
just too damn yellow,
I guess it'll just have to
be your blacksmith friend.
Forget about me, Marty,
and save yourself!
You got one minute
to decide.
You hear me, runt?
One minute!
I've never seen a man so
broken up over a woman.
What did he say her
name was? Cara? Sara?
Clara.
Excuse me.
Ma'am?
But was this man tall with
great big, brown puppy-dog eyes
and long silvery,
flowing hair?
You know him.
Emmett!
Time's up, runt!
Prepare to meet
your maker, blacksmith.
Right here, Tannen!
Draw!
No!
I thought we could
settle this like men.
You thought wrong, dude.
Thank you.
That was good.
You know what I think? No.
I think Buford's
going to jail.
Yeah.
Get him out
of that shit.
Get them!
Buford Tannen,
you're under arrest
for robbing
the Pine City stage.
You got anything to say?
I hate manure.
Look!
Yes!
The train!
Can we make it?
We'll have to cut them
off at Coyote Pass.
Hey! Hey, mister.
Mr. Eastwood.
Here's your gun, mister.
Thanks, kid.
Seamus!
It's worth $12.
Never been used.
Maybe I'll trade it
for a new hat.
Right, and take care of that baby!
I will!
Emmett!
"Time machine. "
Come on, Marty!
Go, Doc.
Come on.
Give me your hand!
Come on, Marty.
Come on. Let's go!
Masks on.
Reach!
Is this a holdup?
It's a science experiment.
Stop the train just before you
hit the switch track up ahead.
Doc!
Uncouple the cars
from the tender!
I've wanted to
do that all my life.
What are these things,
anyway?
My own version
of Pres-to-Logs.
Compressed wood
with anthracite dust
chemically treated to
burn hotter and longer.
I use them in my forge
so I don't have to stoke it.
These three in the furnace
will ignite sequentially,
make the fire
burn hotter,
kick up
the boiler pressure,
and make the train
go faster.
Ready to roll!
Emmett!
Marty, are the
time circuits on?
Check, Doc!
Input the destination time.
October 27, 1985,
11:00 a. m.
Check. Okay, we're cruising at
a steady 25 miles an hour, Doc.
I'm throwing in
the Pres-to-Logs.
Marty, the new gauge
on the dashboard
will tell us
the boiler temperature.
It's color-coded to indicate
when each log will fire.
Green, yellow and red.
Each detonation
will be accompanied
by a sudden burst
of acceleration.
Hopefully, we'll hit
88 miles per hour
before the needle
gets much past 2,000.
Why? What happens
after it hits 2,000?
The whole boiler
explodes!
Perfect!
Hey, Doc!
We just hit 35!
Okay, Marty.
I'm coming aboard!
Emmett!
Come on. Come on.
You better hold
onto something, Doc!
The yellow log
is about to blow!
Golly.
We just passed 40, Doc!
Emmett!
We just passed 45, Doc!
Go for it!
Fifty.
Emmett!
Clara!
I love you!
Doc! Doc!
What's happening?
It's Clara!
She's on the train!
Clara? Perfect.
She's in the cab!
I'm going back for her!
The windmill!
Doc! The windmill! We're going
past 50! You'll never make it!
Then we'll have to
take her back with us!
Keep calling out
the speed!
Clara,
climb out here to me!
I don't know if I can!
You can do it!
Just don't look down!
That's it!
Sixty miles
an hour, Doc!
You're doing fine!
Nice and steady!
Come on!
Just a little further!
I can't, Emmett!
I'm scared!
Seventy!
Keep coming, Clara!
Come on! Come on!
You're doing fine!
Come on!
Nice and easy!
Don't look down! That's
it! You're doing fine!
Doc! The red log
is about to blow!
Clara!
Emmett!
I'm trying
to reach you!
Clara, hold on!
I can't!
Oh!
Doc, I'm gonna slip you
the Hoverboard!
Marty, watch out!
Emmett, help!
Hold on, Clara!
Doc, ready, Doc?
Catch it!
Yes! Yes!
Emmett!
Hold on!
Yes!
What is it? What is it, Pa?
Looks like an airplane without wings.
That ain't no airplane. Look.
Children!
Listen... Whoa.
Hello?
Excuse me.
Sorry about your barn.
It's already mutated
into human form! Shoot it!
Take that, you mutated son of a bitch!
Get away!
Hold it.
Shoot it, Pa!
My pine! Why you...
You space bastard! You killed our pine!
All right. All right. Okay, McFly.
Get a grip on yourself.
It's all a dream.
It's just a very intense dream.
Listen, you got to help me.
Don't stop, Wilbur! Don't!
It can't be.
This is nuts.
Come on.
Perfect.
Remember, fellow
citizens, the future is in your hands.
If you believe in progress,
re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
Progress is his middle name.
Mayor Red Thomas' progress platform
means more jobs, better education,
bigger civic improvements
and lower taxes.
On election day, cast your
vote for a proven leader.
Re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
This has got to be a dream.
Hey, kid. What'd you do? Jump ship?
What?
What's with the life preserver?
I just want to use the phone.
Yeah, it's in the back.
Brown.
Great. You're alive.
Come on.
Do you know where 1640 Riverside...
Are you going to order something, kid?
Yeah. Give me a Tab.
Tab? I can't give you a tab
unless you order something.
Right. Give me a Pepsi Free.
You want a Pepsi, pal,
you're going to pay for it.
Just give me something
without any sugar in it, okay?
Something without sugar.
Hey, McFly.
What do you think you're doing?
Biff.
I'm talking to you,
McFly, you Irish bug!
Hey, Biff. Hey, guys. How are you doing?
You got my homework finished, McFly?
Well, actually, I figured since
it wasn't due till Monday...
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
Think, McFly. Think! Okay.
I got to have time to recopy it.
You realize what would happen
if I hand in my homework
in your handwriting?
I'll get kicked out of school.
You wouldn't want that
to happen, would you?
Would you?
Now, of course not, Biff.
No. I wouldn't want that to happen.
What are you looking at, butthead?
Biff, get a load of this
guy's life preserver.
Dork thinks he's going to drown.
How about my homework, McFly?
Okay, Biff. Well, I'll
finish that on up tonight
and then I'll bring it over
first thing tomorrow morning.
Not too early. I sleep in Sundays.
Oh, McFly, your shoe's untied!
Don't be so gullible, McFly. Okay.
I don't want to see you in here again.
Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
What?
You're George McFly.
Yeah. Who are you?
Say! Why do you let those boys
push you around like that for?
Well, they're bigger than me.
Stand tall, boy. Have
some respect for yourself.
Don't you know, if you let
people walk over you now,
they'll be walking over you
for the rest of your life.
Look at me. You think I'm gonna
spend the rest of my
life in this slop house?
Watch it, Goldie. No, sir!
I'm gonna make something of myself.
I'm going to night school,
and one day, I'm going to be somebody.
That's right. He's going to be mayor.
Yeah, I'm...
Mayor!
Now that's a good idea!
I could run for mayor.
A colored mayor. That'll be the day.
You wait and see, Mr.
Caruthers. I will be mayor.
I'll be the most powerful
man in Hill Valley,
and I'm going to clean up this town.
Good. You can start
by sweeping the floor.
Mayor Goldie Wilson. I
like the sound of that.
Hey, Dad! George! Hey, you on the bike!
He's a peeping Tom.
Dad!
Hey, wait a minute. Wait
a minute. Who are you?
Stella! Another one of these damn kids
jumped in front of my car!
Come on out here! Help
me take him in the house!
Mom? That you?
There, there, now. Just relax.
You've been asleep for
almost nine hours now.
I had a horrible nightmare.
I dreamed that I went back
in time. It was terrible.
Well,
you're safe and sound
now, back in good old 1955.
1955?
You're my... You're my...
My name is Lorraine.
Lorraine Baines.
Yeah.
But you're... You're so...
You're so thin!
Just relax, Calvin. You got
a big bruise on your head.
Where are my pants?
Over there, on my hope chest.
I've never seen purple
underwear before, Calvin.
Calvin? Why do you
keep calling me Calvin?
Well, that is your name,
isn't it? Calvin Klein?
It's written all over your underwear.
Oh, I guess they call you Cal, huh?
No, actually, people call me Marty.
Oh.
Pleased to meet you, Calvin.
Marty.
Klein.
Do you mind if I sit here?
No. Fine.
No. Good. Fine. Good.
That's a big bruise you have there.
Lorraine, are you up there?
Oh, my God! It's my mother!
Quick! Put your pants back on!
So, tell me, Marty,
how long have you been in port?
Excuse me?
I guessed you're a sailor.
That's why you wear that life preserver.
Coast Guard.
Sam, here's the young man
you hit with your car out there.
He's all right. Thank God.
What were you doing in the middle
of the street, a kid your age?
Don't pay attention to him.
He's in one of his moods.
Sam, you quit fiddling with that thing.
Come in here to dinner.
Now, let's see. You
already know Lorraine.
This is Milton, this
is Sally, that's Toby,
and over there in the
playpen is little baby Joey.
So, you're my uncle Joey.
Better get used to these bars, kid.
Yes. Joey just loves
being in his playpen.
He cries whenever we take him out,
so we just leave him
in there all the time.
Well, Marty, I hope you like meatloaf.
Listen, I really ought to...
Sit here, Marty.
Sam, stop fiddling with that thing
and come in here and eat your dinner.
Look at it roll.
Now we can watch Jackie
Gleason while we eat.
It's our first television set.
Dad just picked it up today.
Do you have a television?
Well, yeah. You know
we have two of them.
Wow! You must be rich.
Oh, honey, he's teasing you.
Nobody has two television sets.
Hey. Hey, I've seen this one.
I've seen this one! This is a classic.
This is where Ralph dresses
up as a man from space.
What do you mean, you've
seen this? It's brand-new.
Yeah, well, I saw it on a rerun.
What's a rerun?
You'll find out.
You know, Marty, you look so
familiar to me. Do I know your mother?
Yeah, I think maybe you do.
Oh, then I
want to give her a call.
I don't want her to worry about you.
You can't.
That is, nobody's home.
Oh.
Yet.
Listen, do you know
where Riverside Drive is?
It's on the other end of town.
A block past Maple. East end of town.
Wait a minute, a block past Maple.
That's John F. Kennedy Drive.
Who the hell is John F. Kennedy?
Mother?
With Marty's parents out of town,
don't you think he
ought to spend the night?
I mean, after all, Dad almost
killed him with the car.
That's true, Marty.
I think maybe you
should spend the night.
I think you're our responsibility.
Gee, I don't know.
And he can sleep in my room.
I gotta go! I gotta go!
Thanks very much. It was wonderful.
You were all great. See
you all later. Much later.
He's a very strange young man.
He's an idiot.
Comes from upbringing. His
parents are probably idiots, too.
Lorraine, you ever have a kid
who acts that way, I'll disown you.
Doc?
Don't say a word.
I don't wanna know your name.
I don't want to know anything about you.
Listen, Doc... Quiet!
Doc, it's me, Marty.
Don't tell me anything.
Doc, you got to help... Quiet. Quiet.
I'm going to read your thoughts.
Let's see now. You've come
here from a great distance?
Yeah. Exactly.
Don't tell me!
You want me to buy a subscription
to the Saturday Evening Post.
No.
Not a word. Not a word now!
Quiet.
Donations. You want
me to make a donation
to the Coast Guard Youth Auxiliary.
Doc.
I'm from the future.
I came here in a time
machine that you invented.
Now, I need your help to
get back to the year 1985.
My God.
Do you know what this means?
It means that this damn
thing doesn't work at all!
Doc, you got to help
me. You are the only one
who knows how your time machine works.
Time machine? I haven't
invented any time machine.
Okay. All right, I'll prove it to you.
Look at my driver's
license. Expires 1987.
Look at my birthday,
for crying out loud!
I haven't even been born yet.
And look at this picture.
It's my brother, my sister and me.
Look at her sweatshirt,
Doc. "Class of 1984"?
Pretty mediocre photographic fakery.
They cut off your brother's hair.
I'm telling the truth,
Doc. You got to believe me.
Then tell me, future boy,
Who's President of the
United States in 1985?
Ronald Reagan.
Ronald Reagan? The actor?
Then who's vice president? Jerry Lewis?
I suppose Jane Wyman is the First Lady.
Whoa. Wait, Doc!
And Jack Benny is
secretary of the treasury.
Doc, you gotta listen to me.
I've had enough practical
jokes for one evening.
Good night, future boy!
No, wait, Doc. Doc.
The bruise on your head,
I know how that happened.
You told me the whole story.
You were standing on your toilet
and you were hanging a clock,
and you fell and you hit
your head on the sink.
That's when you came up with
the idea for the flux capacitor,
which is what makes
time travel possible.
There's something wrong with
the starter, so I hid it here.
After I fell off my toilet, I drew this.
The flux capacitor.
It works!
I finally invent something that works!
You bet your ass it works.
Somehow we've got to sneak
this back to my laboratory.
We've got to get you home!
Okay, Doc, this is it.
Never mind that. Never mind that now.
Why, that's me! Look
at me! I'm an old man.
Good evening. I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm standing on the parking
lot at Twin Pines Mall.
Thank God, I've still got my hair.
What's on Earth is
this thing I'm wearing?
This is a radiation suit.
Radiation suit?
Of course. 'Cause of all the
fallout from the atomic wars.
This is truly amazing.
A portable television studio.
No wonder your president
has to be an actor.
He's gotta look good on television.
Whoa. This is it. This is
the part coming up, Doc.
No, no, no, this sucker's electrical,
but I need a nuclear reaction
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts...
What did I just say?
This sucker's electrical,
but I need a nuclear reaction
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts...
1.21 gigawatts!
1.21 gigawatts.
Great Scott!
What the hell is a gigawatt?
How could I have been so
careless? 1.21 gigawatts!
Tom, how am I going to
generate that kind of power?
It can't be done, can it?
Doc, look. All we need
is a little plutonium.
I'm sure that in 1985,
plutonium is available
in every corner drugstore,
but in 1955, it's a
little hard to come by.
Marty, I'm sorry, but I'm
afraid you're stuck here.
Whoa, whoa.
Doc, stuck here? I can't be
stuck here. I got a life in 1985.
I got a girl.
Is she pretty?
Doc, she's beautiful.
She's crazy about me.
Look at this. Look what she wrote
here, Doc. I mean, that says it all.
Doc, you're my only hope.
Marty, I'm sorry, but the only
power source capable of generating
1.21 gigawatts of electricity
is a bolt of lightning.
What did you say?
A bolt of lightning.
Unfortunately, you never know
when or where it's ever going to strike.
We do now.
This is it! This is the answer.
It says here that a bolt of lightning
is going to strike the clock tower
at precisely 10:04 p.m.
Next Saturday night!
If we could somehow
harness this lightning,
channel it into the flux capacitor,
it just might work.
Next Saturday night, we're
sending you back to the future!
Okay, all right. Saturday's
good. Saturday's good.
I can spend a week in 1955.
I can hang out. You can show me around.
Marty, that is completely
out of the question.
You must not leave this house.
You must not see anybody
or talk to anybody.
Anything you do can have serious
repercussions on future events.
Do you understand?
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
Marty,
have you interacted with
anybody else today, besides me?
Yeah, well, I might've sort
of bumped into my parents.
Great Scott!
Let me see that photograph
again of your brother.
Just as I thought. This proves
my theory. Look at your brother.
His head's gone.
It's like it's been erased.
Erased from existence.
Whoa.
They really cleaned this
place up. Looks brand-new.
Now remember.
According to my theory, you interfered
with your parents' first meeting.
If they don't meet,
they won't fall in love,
they won't get married
and they won't have kids.
That's why your older brother's
disappearing from that photograph.
Your sister will follow, and
unless you repair the damage,
you'll be next.
Sounds pretty heavy.
Weight has nothing to do with it.
Which one's your pop?
That's him.
Okay. Okay, you guys.
Very funny. You guys
are being real mature.
Maybe you were adopted.
Okay, real mature, guys.
Okay, pick up my books.
McFly.
That's Strickland.
Jesus, didn't that guy ever have hair?
Shape up, man. You're a slacker.
Do you want to be a slacker
for the rest of your life?
No.
What did your mother
ever see in that kid?
I don't know, Doc.
I guess she felt sorry for him
'cause her dad hit him with the car.
Hit me with the car.
That's the Florence Nightingale effect.
It happens in hospitals when nurses
fall in love with their patients.
Go to it, kid.
Hey, George, buddy.
I have been looking all over for you.
You remember me, the guy who
saved your life the other day?
Oh.
Yeah. Good.
There's somebody I'd like you to meet.
Lorraine?
Calvin!
I'd like you to meet my
good friend George McFly.
Hi. It's really a pleasure to meet you.
How's your head?
Good. Fine.
Oh. I've been so worried about you
ever since you ran off the other night.
Are you okay? Yeah.
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Come on!
Isn't he a dreamboat?
Doc, she didn't even look at him.
This is more serious than I thought.
Apparently, your mother is
amorously infatuated with you,
instead of your father.
Whoa. Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you trying to tell me that
my mother has got the hots for me?
Precisely.
Whoa. This is heavy.
There's that word again. "Heavy."
Why are things so heavy in the future?
Is there a problem with the
Earth's gravitational pull?
What? The only way
we're going to get those
two to successfully mate
is if they're alone together,
so you've got to get your
father and mother to interact
in some sort of social...
What? You mean like a date? Right!
What kind of date? I don't know.
What do kids do in the '50s?
They're your parents.
You must know them.
What are their common interests?
What do they like to do together?
Nothing.
Look! There's a rhythmic
ceremonial ritual coming up.
Of course! The Enchantment
Under the Sea dance!
They're supposed to go to this.
That's where they kiss
for the first time.
All right, kid.
You stick to your father like glue
and make sure he takes
her to that dance.
George, buddy.
Remember that girl I
introduced you to, Lorraine?
What are you writing?
Uh... Stories.
Science fiction stories about visitors
coming down to Earth from other planets.
Get out of town! I didn't
know you did anything creative.
Let me read some.
Oh. No, no, no, no.
I never let anybody read my stories.
Why not?
Well, what if they didn't like them?
What if they told me I was no good?
I guess that would be pretty
hard for somebody to understand.
No. No, not hard at all.
So, anyway, George. About Lorraine.
She really likes you.
She told me to tell you
that she wants you to ask her
to the Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
Really? Oh, yeah.
All you got to do is go
over there and ask her.
What? Right here, right
now, in the cafeteria?
What if she said no?
I don't know if I could take
that kind of a rejection.
Besides, I think she'd
rather go with somebody else.
Who?
Biff.
Don't kid around. Come on.
I'm gonna leave.
You want it. You know you want it.
You know you want me to give it to you.
Shut your filthy mouth.
I'm not that kind of girl.
Maybe you are and you
just don't know it yet.
Get your meat hooks off of me.
You heard her.
She said, get your meat hooks off.
Please.
So what's it to you, butthead?
You know, you been looking for a fight.
Since you're new here, I'm
going to cut you a break, today.
So, why don't you make like
a tree and get out of here.
George!
Why do you keep following me around?
Look, George... I'm telling you, George,
if you do not ask
Lorraine to that dance,
I'm gonna regret it
for the rest of my life.
But I can't go to the dance.
I'll miss my favorite television
program, Science Fiction Theatre.
Yeah, but, George, Lorraine
wants to go with you.
Give her a break.
Look, I'm just not ready to
ask Lorraine out to the dance,
and not you or anybody
else on this planet
is going to make me change my mind.
Science Fiction Theatre.
Who are you?
Silence, Earthling.
My name is Darth Vader.
I am an extraterrestrial
from the planet Vulcan.
Marty!
Marty! Marty!
Hey, George, buddy.
You weren't at school. What
have you been doing all day?
I overslept. Look, I need your help.
I have to ask Lorraine out,
but I don't know how to do it.
All right. Okay, listen, keep your
pants on. She's over in the cafe.
God! How do you...
What made you change your mind, George?
Last night, Darth Vader
came down from Planet Vulcan
and told me that if I didn't take
Lorraine out, that he'd melt my brain.
Let's just keep this brain-melting
stuff to ourselves, okay?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
All right, okay. There she is, George.
Now just go in there and invite her.
Okay. But I don't know what to say.
Just say anything, George.
Say whatever's natural, the first
thing that comes into your mind.
Nothing's coming to my mind.
Jesus, George, it's a
wonder I was even born.
What? What?
Nothing. Nothing. Nothing.
Look, tell her destiny
brought you together.
Tell her that she is
the most beautiful girl
you have ever seen in the world.
Girls like that stuff.
What are you doing, George?
I'm writing this down.
This is good stuff.
Yeah. Okay, let's go.
Can you take care of that? Right.
Lou, give me a milk.
Chocolate.
Lorraine. My density
has popped me to you.
What?
Oh.
What I meant to say was...
Wait a minute. Don't I
know you from somewhere?
Yes.
Yes. I'm George. George McFly.
I'm your density.
I mean,
your destiny.
Oh.
Hey, McFly.
I thought I told you
never to come in here.
Well, it's going to cost you.
How much money you got on you?
How much do you want, Biff?
All right, punk.
Now I'm going to...
Whoa, whoa, Biff. What's that?
That's Calvin Klein.
Oh, my God, he's a dream.
Whoa, whoa.
Kid! Kid, stop! Stop!
Hey!
I'll get it
back to you, all right?
You broke it!
Come back here!
Wow. Look at him go!
Get him!
To the car! Go! Go!
What's that thing he's on?
It's a board with wheels.
He's an absolute dream.
Come on, come on!
Look out for the car!
Whoa!
I'm going to ram him.
Shit!
Ooh!
Thanks a lot, kid.
I'm going to get that son of a bitch.
Where does he come from?
Yeah, where does he live?
I don't know, but I'm going to find out.
Oh, my God.
They found me. I don't
know how, but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Oh, my God.
They found me. I don't
know how, but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Doc?
Hi, Marty. I didn't hear you come in.
Fascinating device, this video unit.
Listen, Doc.
You know, there's something
I haven't told you about the night
we made that tape. Please,
Marty, don't tell me.
No man should know too
much about his own destiny.
You don't understand. I do understand.
If I know too much about my own future,
I can endanger my own existence.
Just as you've endangered yours.
You're right. Now...
Let me show you my plan
for sending you home.
Please excuse the crudity of this model.
I didn't have time to build
it to scale or paint it.
It's good. Thank you. Thank you.
Okay, now.
We run some industrial-strength
electrical cable
from the top of the clock tower
down, suspending it over the street
between these two lamp posts.
Meanwhile, we've
outfitted the time vehicle
with this big pole and hook,
which runs directly
into the flux capacitor.
At the calculated moment, you
start off from down the street,
driving directly toward the cable,
accelerating to 88 miles per hour.
According to the flyer, at precisely
10:04 p.m. This Saturday night,
lightning will strike the clock
tower, electrifying the cable
just as the connecting
hook makes contact
thereby sending 1.21 gigawatts
into the flux capacitor
and sending you back to 1985.
All right, now. Watch this.
You wind up the car and release it.
I'll simulate the lightning.
Ready.
Set.
Release.
You're instilling me with
a lot of confidence, Doc.
Don't worry. I'll take
care of the lightning.
You take care of your pop.
By the way, what happened
today? Did he ask her out?
I think so.
What did she say?
It's your mom! She's tracked you down!
Quick! Let's cover the time machine.
Hi, Cal... Marty.
Mom. Lorraine.
How did you know I was here?
I followed you.
Oh. This is my doc...
My uncle, Doc Brown.
Hi. Hi.
Marty, this may seem a little forward,
but I was kind of
wondering if you'd ask me
to the Enchantment Under
the Sea dance on Saturday.
Wow, you mean... You
mean nobody's asked you?
No. Not yet.
What about George?
George McFly?
He's kind of cute and all, but not...
Well, I think a man should be strong,
so he can stand up for himself
and protect the woman he loves.
Don't you?
Yeah.
I still don't understand.
How am I supposed to
go to the dance with her
if she's already going
to the dance with you?
Well, because, George,
she wants to go with you.
She just doesn't know it yet.
That's why we got to show her
that you, George McFly, are a fighter.
You're somebody who's
gonna stand up for yourself,
somebody who's gonna protect her.
Yeah, but I've never picked
a fight in my entire life.
Look, you're not going to
be picking a fight, Dad.
Daddy-o.
You're coming to her rescue, right?
Okay, let's go over the plan again.
8:55, where are you going to be?
I'm going to be at the dance.
Right. And where am I going to be?
You're gonna be in the car with her.
Right, okay. So, right around 9:00,
she's going to get very angry with me.
Why is she going to get angry with you?
Well, because, George,
nice girls get angry
when guys take advantage of them.
You mean you're going
to go touch her on her...
No. No, George, look.
It's just an act, right?
Okay. So, 9:00, you're strolling
through the parking lot.
You see us struggling in the car.
You walk up, you open
the door, and you say...
Your line, George.
Oh!
Hey, you, get your damn hands off her!
You really think I ought to swear?
Yes, definitely.
God damn it, George, swear.
Okay. So, now you come up.
You punch me in the stomach.
I'm out for the count, right?
And you and Lorraine
live happily ever after.
You make it sound so easy.
I just... I wish I wasn't so scared.
George, there's nothing to be scared of.
All it takes is a
little self-confidence.
You know, if you put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
This is heavy, Doc. I mean, it's
like I was just here yesterday.
You were here yesterday,
Marty. You were.
Amazing, isn't it?
All right, sunrise should
be in about 22 minutes.
You go into town. Track
down Young Biff and tail him.
Sometime today,
Old Biff will show up
to give Young Biff
the almanac.
Above all you, must not
interfere with that event.
We must let Old Biff believe he's
succeeded, so that he'll leave 1955
and bring the DeLorean
back to the future.
Right.
Once Old Biff is gone, grab the
almanac any way that you can.
Remember, both of our
futures depend on this.
You don't have to
remind me of that, Doc.
Here's some binoculars and a
walkie-talkie so we can keep in contact.
I'll stay here and try to repair
the short in the time circuit.
That way, we don't risk anyone
else stealing the time machine,
and I won't risk accidentally
running into my other self.
Other self?
Yes. There are now
two of me here,
and there are
two of you here.
The other me is the Dr.
Emmett Brown from 1955,
the younger me that helps the
other you get back to 1985.
Remember the lightning bolt
at the clock tower?
Yeah. That event doesn't
happen until tonight,
so you must be very careful
not to run into your other self.
Let me give you
some money.
I have to be prepared for
all monetary possibilities.
Get yourself
some '50s clothes.
Check, Doc.
Something inconspicuous.
Doc. Come in, Doc.
This is Marty. Over.
Roger, Marty. This is Doc.
Are you there?
Yeah, Doc.
I'm at the address.
It's the only Tannen
in the book,
but I don't think
this is Biff's house.
It looks like some
old lady lives here.
Biff!
Yeah.
Where are you
going, Biff?
I'm going to get
my car, Grandma.
When are you
coming back?
My feet hurt, and I want
you to rub my toes some more.
Shut up,
you old bag.
Give us
our ball back.
What ball?
That ball!
What ball are
you talking about?
Give us our ball!
What ball?
Biff!
Is this your ball?
Yeah!
Is it your ball?
You want it back?
Yeah.
Go get it.
Doc, it is Biff's house.
I'm on him. Over.
Hey.
Looking good, Terry.
Hey, Biff, she's all
fixed up just like new,
but I couldn't
get her started.
You got some kind of
kill switch on this thing?
No, you just gotta
have the right touch.
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Yeah, the bill
comes to $302.57.
300 bucks?
300 bucks for
a couple of dents?
No, hey,
that's bullshit, Terry.
No, Biff,
it was horse shit.
The whole car
was full of it.
We had to pay Old Man Jones
80 bucks to haul it away.
Old Man Jones
probably resold it, too.
Now I ought to get
something for that.
You want
something for it?
We'll go inside. You
can call Old Man Jones.
If he wants to
give you a refund...
It's 300 bucks, Terry.
If I catch the guy that caused
this, I'll break his neck.
The manure.
I remember that.
Four cans of Valvoline
is fair, Biff.
Four cans
for a $300 job?
I couldn't even
have lunch in the shop.
Makes me nauseous. I
should get a case of oil
out of you for a 300 buck
job. You've been inside.
It smells worse than the
bathroom at a gas station.
You robbed me again,
Terry. Yeah, yeah.
The smell's never
gonna go away, Biff.
Never gonna go away.
Last time I do you a favor.
Last time. Thanks a lot.
Let me see.
It's perfect,
Lorraine.
Oh, look at it!
You're going to
look so good!
You're going
to look...
Well, lookey
what we have here.
Hey, nice dress,
Lorraine.
Although, I think you'd look
better wearing nothing at all.
Biff, why don't you take a
long walk off a short pier?
Hey, listen, Lorraine.
There's that dance at
school tonight, right.
Now that
my car's all fixed,
I figure
I'd cut you a break
and give you
the honor of going
with the best-looking
guy in school.
Yeah, well, I'm busy.
Yeah, doing what?
Washing my hair.
That's about as funny as a
screen door on a battleship.
Screen door on
a submarine, you dork.
Look, Biff, somebody already
asked me to the dance.
Who? That bug
George McFly?
I'm going with
Calvin Klein, okay?
Calvin Klein?
No, it's not okay.
You're going
with me, understand?
Get your cooties
off me!
When are you gonna get it through
your thick skull, Lorraine?
You're my girl.
Biff Tannen,
I wouldn't be your girl
even if you had
a million dollars!
Yes, you will! It's
you and me, Lorraine.
Watch it!
It's meant to be.
I'm going to marry
you someday, Lorraine.
Someday you'll
be my wife!
You always did
have a way with women.
Get the hell out
of my car, old man.
You want to marry
that girl, Biff?
I can help
make it happen.
Oh, yeah? Who are you,
Miss Lonely-Hearts?
Just get in the car,
butthead.
Who are you calling
butthead, butthead?
How do you know
how to do that?
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Just get in the car, Tannen.
Today's your lucky day.
Hey! Hey! Hey, watch where
you're driving, old man.
If you dent this car,
I'll kill you.
This cost me
300 bucks!
Would you shut up
about the car?
Hey, and another thing. How
do you know where I live?
Let's just say
we're related, Biff.
And that being the case, I
got a little present for you.
Something that'll
make you rich.
You want to be rich,
don't you?
Oh, yeah. Sure. Right.
That's rich.
You're going
to make me rich?
You see this book? This
book tells the future.
Tells the results of
every major sports event
till the end
of the century.
Football, baseball,
horse races, boxing.
The information in here is worth
millions, and I'm giving it to you.
Well, that's very nice.
Thank you very much.
Now, why don't you make like
a tree and get out of here?
It's leave, you idiot.
Make like a tree and leave.
You sound like a damn fool
when you say it wrong.
All right, then, leave and
take your book with you.
Don't you get it? You could
make a fortune with this book.
Let me show you.
UCLA trails 17-16.
It's 4th and 11 with only
18 seconds left of this game.
I'd say it's
all over for UCLA.
Bet you a million bucks
UCLA wins it 19-17.
What are you,
deaf, old man?
He just said it was over.
You lost.
Oh, yeah?
Here comes Decker
with the kick.
It's up.
It looks good, folks!
It looks very good. Field
goal! UCLA wins 19-17.
Listen to that Coliseum
crowd go wild. Jim Decker...
All right, pops.
What's the gag?
How did you know what
the score was gonna be?
I told you.
It's in this book.
All you gotta do is bet on the
winner, and you'll never lose.
All right.
I'll take a look at it.
You damn fool!
Never, never leave
this book laying around.
Don't you have a safe?
No, you don't have a safe.
Get a safe.
Keep it locked up.
And until then, keep
it on you like this.
Hey, what are you doing?
And don't tell anybody about it, either.
And there's
one more thing.
One day, a kid or a
crazy, wild-eyed old man
who claims to
be a scientist
is going to come around
asking about this...
If that ever happens...
I'm trapped. Doc.
Doc, come in, Doc.
Marty, what's the report?
Biff's gone.
He's got the book.
The old man's gone, too.
I'm locked in Biff's garage.
You gotta fly
the DeLorean over here
and get me
the hell out of here.
The address is
1809 Mason Street.
I can't take the DeLorean
out in the daylight,
but don't worry, Marty.
Somehow I'll get over there.
Doc, wait a minute.
Doc. Hey, Doc. Doc.
Perfect.
I told you, Grandma.
I'm going to the dance.
When you coming home?
The dance.
I'll get home
when I get home.
Don't forget to turn
off the garage light.
Marty. Marty!
Marty.
Marty, Marty. Damn!
Where is that kid?
...Hill Valley area
weather this Saturday night.
Mostly clear, with
some scattered clouds.
Lows tonight in the upper 40s.
Are you sure about this storm?
Since when can weathermen predict
the weather, let alone the future?
You know, Marty, I'm going
to be very sad to see you go.
You've really made a
difference in my life.
You've given me something to shoot for.
Just knowing that I'm going
to be around to see 1985.
That I'm going to succeed in this!
That I'm going to have a
chance to travel through time!
It's going to be really hard waiting
30 years before I can talk to you
about everything that's
happened in the past few days.
I'm really going to miss you, Marty.
I'm really going to miss you.
Doc, about the future...
No!
Marty! We've already agreed
that having information about the future
can be extremely dangerous.
Even if your intentions are good,
it can backfire drastically.
Whatever you've got to tell me,
I'll find out through the
natural course of time.
Doc. Doc, come in.
Come in, Doc.
Marty! Marty, come in.
Doc.
Marty.
Oh, my...
Great Scott.
Oh, my God.
Doc, Doc, come in.
Marty,
what happened to you?
I went to Biff's house,
and you weren't there.
You must have
just missed me.
I'm in the back
of Biff's car.
He's on his way to the
Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
Marty, listen, we may have
to abort this entire plan.
It's getting
much too dangerous.
Don't worry. The book
is on Biff's dashboard.
I'll grab it as soon
as we get to the school.
Marty, you must
be extremely careful
not to run into
your other self.
My other self?
Yes.
Remember, your mother is at that
exact same dance with you. Yeah.
Right. This could
get heavy, Doc.
Heavy, heavy.
Marty, whatever happens, you must
not let your other self see you!
The consequences
could be disastrous.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, you with the hat.
Who, me?
Yes.
Be a pal and hand me a five-eighths
inch wrench out of that toolbox.
Five-eighths?
Don't you mean
three-quarters?
Why, you're right.
I presume you're conducting
some sort of weather experiment.
That's right.
How did you know that?
I happen to have had a little
experience in this area.
Yes, well, I'm hoping to
see some lightning tonight.
Although, the weatherman says
there's not gonna be any rain.
There's going to be
plenty of rain, all right.
Wind, thunder,
lightning.
It's gonna be one
hell of a storm.
Well, thanks.
Nice talking to you.
Maybe we'll bump into each other
some time again in the future.
Or in the past.
"Dear Dr. Brown.
"On the night that I go back in time,
"you will be
"shot by terrorists.
"Please take whatever
precautions are necessary
"to prevent this terrible disaster.
"Your friend,
"Marty."
'Evening, Dr. Brown.
What's with the wire?
Oh, just a little weather experiment.
What you got under here?
No! Don't touch that!
Some new, specialized
weather-sensing equipment.
You got a permit for that?
Of course I do.
Just a second. Let me
see if I can find it here.
Doc, Doc! Come in!
Where's that punk
Calvin Klein, anyway?
How am I
supposed to know, Biff?
I ain't his secretary.
Well, go find him. He caused
300 bucks damage to my car,
and I owe him a knuckle
sandwich. Get going!
Drink up, Biff.
Yeah, thanks.
Ain't you coming?
I'm reading.
Do you mind if we park for a while?
That's a great idea. I'd love to park.
Huh?
Marty, I'm almost 18 years old.
It's not like I've never parked before.
What?
We're going to take a little break,
but we'll be back in a while,
so don't nobody go nowhere.
Well, well, well,
Mr. Tannen.
How nice
to see you here.
Why, Mr. Strickland,
it's nice to see you, sir.
Is that liquor
I smell, Tannen?
I wouldn't know.
I don't know what
liquor smells like,
'cause I'm too
young to drink it.
I see.
And what have we here?
Sports statistics, interesting
subject. Homework, Tannen?
No, it ain't homework,
'cause I ain't at home.
You've got a real
attitude problem.
You know that, Tannen?
Just watch it.
Because one day,
I'll have you
right where I want you
in detention.
Slacker!
Marty, you seem so
nervous. Is something wrong?
No.
Lorraine! Lorraine, what are you doing?
I swiped it from the old
lady's liquor cabinet.
Yeah, well, you shouldn't drink.
Why not?
Because you...
You might regret it later in life.
Marty, don't be such a square.
Everybody who's anybody drinks.
Jesus,
you smoke, too?
Marty, you're beginning to
sound just like my mother.
Yeah, right.
When I have kids, I'm going to
let them do anything they want.
Anything at all.
Yeah, I'd like to
have that in writing.
Yeah, me, too.
Marty,
why are you so nervous?
Lorraine.
Have you ever been in a situation
where you knew you had
to act a certain way,
but when you got there, you didn't know
if you could go through with it?
You mean like how you're
supposed to act on a first date?
Sort of.
I think I know exactly what you mean.
You do?
You know what I do in those situations?
What?
I don't worry.
This is all wrong. I
don't know what it is.
But when I kiss you,
it's like I'm kissing
my brother.
I guess that doesn't
make any sense, does it?
Believe me, it makes perfect sense.
Somebody's coming.
You caused 300 bucks damage
to my car, you son of a bitch.
And I'm going to take it
out of your ass. Hold him.
Let him go, Biff. You're drunk.
Well, look-ey what we have here.
No, no! You're staying right
here with me. Come on, Lorraine.
Let me go!
Leave her alone, you bastard!
Take him in back, all
right? I'll be right there.
Just admit that
you want it. Come on.
Well, go on. This ain't no peep show.
Hey, let's put him in there.
Yeah!
That's for messing up my hair.
What the hell are you doing to my car?
Hey, beat it, spook.
This don't concern you.
Who you calling "spook," peckerwood?
Hey, hey, listen, guys...
Look, I don't want to mess
with no reefer addicts, okay?
Get home to your mama, boy.
Biff!
Hurry, Biff!
Let me out of here!
Reginald, where are your keys?
The keys are in the trunk.
Say that again?
I said, the keys are in here.
Yes!
No!
"Oh L L?"
Doc! Doc!
Hey, you.
Doc, come in!
Marty, what's up?
Oh.
I think you got the wrong car, McFly.
George, help me! Please!
Just turn around, McFly, and walk away.
Please, George.
Are you deaf, McFly?
Close the door and beat it.
No, Biff. You leave her alone.
Doc! I'm in trouble.
I blew it.
Where's the book?
Biff must still
have it with him.
All I got is
the damn cover.
And where's Biff?
You're asking for it.
I don't know.
Don't you have any
idea where he is?
No! I mean, he could
be anywhere by now.
Marty, the entire
future depends on you
finding Biff and
getting that book back!
I know.
I just don't know where...
Stop it!
Stop it, Biff. You'll
break his arm. Stop it!
Of course!
I gotta go.
I got one chance!
My old man is
about to deck Biff!
Give me a hand here, Reginald.
Damn it, man! I sliced my hand!
Whose are these? Mine.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
...leave him alone!
Let him go! Let him go!
Yes!
Talk about dj vu.
Are you okay?
The storm.
Okay, everybody,
let's back up now.
Let's back up. Let's
everybody just back up
and give him a little bit of room, okay.
A little bit of air.
It's okay.
I know CPR. I know CPR.
Hey.
What's CPR?
You!
He's fine.
Hey, did you
just take his wallet?
He just took
that guy's wallet.
Hey, guys, you gotta get back
in there and finish the dance.
Hey, man. Look at Marvin's hand.
He can't play with his hand like that,
and we can't play without him.
Yeah, well. Look,
Marvin, you got to play.
See, that's where they kiss for
the first time on the dance floor.
And if there's no
music, they can't dance.
If they can't dance, they can't kiss.
If they can't kiss, they can't
fall in love and I'm history.
Hey, man, the dance is over
unless you know somebody
else that can play the guitar.
Doc, success.
I got it.
Thank goodness.
Great, Marty.
As soon as I reload
the fusion generator,
I'll meet you on the roof
of the high school gym.
On the roof. 10-4.
Hey, it's him!
Hey, he's in disguise.
Guys, what's that?
Come on!
Let's get him!
Damn!
This is for all you lovers out there.
Earth angel, Earth angel
Will you be mine?
My darling dear
George, aren't you going to kiss me?
I don't know.
Scram, McFly. I'm cutting in.
Earth angel, Earth angel
The one I adore
Hey, boy, you all right?
I can't play.
George!
George.
Excuse me.
The vision of your happiness
Earth angel, Earth angel
Please be mine
My darling dear
Love you for all time
I'm just a fool
A fool in love
with you
All right!
Let's do another one.
-Where did he go?
-Come on, man. Let's do
something that really cooks.
Something that cooks.
All right.
All right!
Look! How did he
get up on stage?
All right, this is an oldie, but...
-Well...
-When he gets
down, we're gonna nail him.
How the hell did he
change his clothes so fast?
Well, it's an oldie where I come from.
All right, guys, listen,
this is a blues riff in B.
Watch me for the changes,
and try and keep up, okay?
Doc. Doc, come in!
Marty, come in.
Listen, Biff's guys chased me into
the gym, and they're going to jump me.
Then get out of there!
No, Doc, not me.
The other me.
The one that's up on stage
playing Johnny B. Goode.
Great Scott!
Your other self will miss
the lightning bolt
at the clock tower,
you won't get back to the future,
and we'll have a major paradox!
Wait, wait, wait.
A paradox?
You mean one of those things
that can destroy the universe?
Precisely. Marty, you have to
stop those guys at all costs,
but without being seen by your
other self or your parents.
10-4.
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go
Hey, George, I heard you
laid out Biff. Nice going.
George, you ever think of
running for class president?
Johnny B. Goode
Go, Johnny, go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
What the hell?
Where is he?
Who?
Calvin Klein.
The guy with the hat,
where is he?
Oh. He went that way.
I think he took your wallet.
I think he took his wallet.
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
Go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
Chuck! Chuck, it's Marvin.
Your cousin, Marvin Berry.
You know that new sound
you're looking for?
Well, listen to this.
I guess you guys aren't
ready for that yet.
But your kids are going to love it.
Hey, Doc, success.
Everything's cool.
Great. I'll be landing at the
school roof in about one minute.
I'll be there.
Lorraine.
Marty, that was
very interesting music.
Yeah.
I hope you don't mind,
but George asked if
he could take me home.
Great! Good. Good, Lorraine.
I had a feeling about you two.
I have a feeling, too.
Hey, butthead!
You think that stupid
disguise would get by me?
Let's have it out.
You and me, right now.
No, thanks.
Well, good luck, you guys.
What's the matter?
-Where are you going?
-Oh
One other thing. If
you guys ever have kids,
and one of them, when
he's eight years old,
accidentally sets fire
to the living room rug,
go easy on him.
Okay.
Are you chicken?
That's it, isn't it?
Nothing but a little chicken.
Nobody
calls me chicken.
Marty. Such a nice name.
What the hell?
You steal my stuff?
And this one's
for my car!
Doc!
Doc! I blew it.
Biff nailed me.
He took the book.
He drove away
with it in his car.
It's my fault, Doc. I should
have got out of there sooner.
No time for that now.
Which way did he go?
East towards
the River Road Tunnel.
Get in!
Yes!
There he is, Doc!
Let's land on him.
We'll cripple his car.
Marty, he's in a '46 Ford.
We're a DeLorean.
He'd rip through us
like we were tin foil.
So what do we do?
I have a plan.
Repeating tonight's
earlier weather bulletin,
a severe thunderstorm is
heading for Hill Valley.
Serving Hill Valley
and all of Hill County,
you're tuned to KKHV,
the voice of Hill Valley.
Turning to
community calendar,
the Hill Valley
Women's Club bake sale
will be held
tomorrow afternoon
from 2:00 to 5:00 at the
community center on Forest Road.
For you sports fans
out there,
there was a lot of action
today in college football.
Here's what happened
to the top 10.
UCLA narrowly
defeated Washington 19-17.
Michigan State
crushed Minnesota 42-14.
Ohio State
beat Iowa 20-10.
Michigan
blanked Indiana 30-0.
Shit.
It was Notre Dame over
North Carolina, 27-7.
Son of a bitch.
Oklahoma ripped
Iowa State 52-0.
West Virginia lost
to Pittsburgh 26-7.
Texas A&M over Rice 20-10.
Maryland
defeated Clemson 25-12,
and it was Texas
Christian over Texas 47-20.
Repeating tonight's earlier
weather bulletin, a severe...
You again?
Give me that book.
Let it go!
Whoa!
Let go of the car!
That'll teach him.
Oh!
Go, Doc!
Hold on, Marty!
Shit!
Yes!
Manure!
I hate manure!
Damn! Where is that kid?
Damn!
Damn! Damn!
You're late! Do you
have no concept of time?
Hey, come on. I had to change.
Do you think I'm going
back in that zoot suit?
The old man really
came through. It worked.
He laid out Biff in one punch.
I didn't know he had it in him.
He's never stood up to Biff in his life.
Never?
No. Why? What's the matter?
All right! Let's set
your destination time.
This is the exact time you left.
Let's send you back at
exactly the same time.
It'll be like you never left.
Now, I painted a white line
on the street way over there.
That's where you'll start from.
I've calculated the precise distance,
taking into account
the acceleration speed
and wind resistance retroactive
from the moment the lightning strikes,
which will be in exactly
7 minutes and 22 seconds.
When this alarm goes
off, you hit the gas.
Right.
Well, I guess that's everything.
Thanks.
Thank you.
See you in about 30 years.
I hope so.
Don't worry!
As long as you hit that wire
with the connecting hook at
precisely 88 miles an hour,
the instant the lightning
strikes the tower
everything will be fine.
Right.
What's the meaning of this?
You'll find out in 30 years.
It's about the future, isn't it?
It's information about the future.
Wait a minute.
I warned you about this, kid.
The consequences could be disastrous!
Doc, that's a risk you're
going to have to take.
Your life depends on it!
No!
I refuse to accept the responsibility.
In that case, I'll
tell you straight out.
Great Scott!
You get the cable, I'll
throw the rope down to you.
Right! I got it!
Doc, is everything
all right? Over.
10-4, Marty, but it's pretty
miserable flying weather.
Much too turbulent to make a
landing from this direction.
I'll have to circle around and
make a long approach from the south.
Have you got the book?
In my hand, Doc!
I got it in my hand!
Burn it!
Check!
Doc! Doc!
That newspaper changed.
Doc, my father's alive!
That means everything's
back to normal, right?
Mission accomplished.
That means Jennifer's okay
and Einie's okay, right?
That's right, Marty.
It's the ripple effect.
The future is back,
so let's go home.
Right. Let's get our
asses back to the...
Doc, Doc,
are you okay?
That was a close one, Marty.
I almost bought the farm.
Well, be careful. You don't
want to get struck by lightning.
Doc.
Doc?
Doc, come in, Doc.
Doc, do you read me?
Do you read me, Doc?
Come in. Doc.
Oh, no.
He's gone.
The doc's gone.
Mr. McFly!
Huh?
Is your name
Marty McFly?
Yeah.
I've got something for you.
A letter.
A letter for me?
That's impossible.
Who the hell are you?
Western Union.
Actually, a bunch of us at
the office were kind of hoping
maybe you could shed
some light on the subject.
See, we've had that envelope in our
possession for the past 70 years.
It was given to us with
the explicit instructions
that it be delivered to a
young man with your description
answering to the name of
Marty at this exact location
at this exact minute,
November 12, 1955.
We have a little bet
going as to whether
this Marty would
actually be here.
Looks like I lost.
Did you say 70 years?
Yeah, 70 years, 2 months,
12 days to be exact.
Here sign on line 6,
please.
Here you are.
It's from the doc!
"Dear Marty, if my
calculations are correct,
"you will receive this
letter immediately after
"you saw the DeLorean
struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you
that I'm alive and well.
"I've been living happily these
past eight months in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt... "
1885!
"September, 1885."
Wait, wait, kid! Wait a
minute. What's this all about?
He's alive!
The doc's alive!
He's in the Old West,
but he's alive.
Yeah, but, kid,
you all right?
Do you need any help?
There's only one man
who can help me.
Doc!
Come on, come on. Let's go!
All right! Take it up!
Go!
Doc!
What?
I have to tell you about the future.
I have to tell you about the future!
What?
On the night I go back
in time, you get...
Doc!
Go!
No, Doc!
Look at the time!
You've got less than four
minutes. Please, hurry!
Yeah!
Damn it, Doc! Why did you
have to tear up that letter?
If I only had more time.
Wait a minute. I got
all the time I want.
I got a time machine. I can
just go back early and warn him.
Okay. Ten minutes ought to do it.
Okay. Time circuit's on.
Flux capacitor, fluxing.
Engine running. All right.
No. No, no.
Come on. Not this
time. Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Here we go. Here we
go. This time. Come on.
Please. Please. Come on!
Doc.
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Doc! Doc!
What?
Okay, relax, Doc. It's
me. It's me! It's Marty.
No, it can't be. I just
sent you back to the future.
Yeah. No, I know.
You did send me
back to the future,
but I'm back.
I'm back
from the future.
Great Scott!
Hey, kids, what time is it?
Howdy Doody time!
Great Scott!
It's Howdy Doody Time
Bob Smith and Howdy Do
Say Howdy Do to you
Howdy Doody time?
Date. Sunday, November
13, 1955. 7:01 a. m.
Last night's
time travel experiment
was apparently
a complete success.
Lightning struck the clock
tower at precisely 10:04 p. m.
Sending the necessary 1.21
gigawatts into the time vehicle,
which vanished in a
brilliant flash of light
leaving a pair of
fire trails behind.
I, therefore, assume that
Marty and the time vehicle
were transported forward
through time into the year 1985.
After that...
After that, I can't
recall what happened.
In fact, I don't even
remember how I got home.
Perhaps
the gigawatt discharge
coupled with the temporal
displacement field
generated by
the time vehicle
caused a disruption
of my own brain waves
resulting in a condition
of momentary amnesia.
Indeed, I now recall
that moments
after the time vehicle
disappeared
into the future,
I saw a vision
of Marty saying
he had come back
from the future.
Hey, Doc!
Undoubtedly, this was some
sort of residual image...
Doc.
Doc, calm down, okay. Just
calm down. It's me. It's Marty.
No, it can't be you! I
sent you back to the future!
That's right, Doc.
That's right,
but I came back again. I
came back from the future.
Don't you
remember last night?
You fainted.
I brought you home.
This can't be happening!
You can't be here!
It doesn't make sense
for you to be here!
I refuse to even believe
that you are here!
Doc, I am here,
and it does make sense.
Look, I came back to
1955 again with you,
the you from 1985, 'cause we
had to get a book from Biff!
So once I got
the book back,
you, that is the you
from 1985,
were in the DeLorean, and
it got struck by lightning,
and you got
sent back to 1885!
1885?
It's a very interesting
story, future boy,
but there's just one little
thing that doesn't make sense.
If the me of the future
is now in the past,
how could you
possibly know about it?
You sent me a letter.
"Dear Marty, if my
calculations are correct,
"you will receive this
letter immediately after
"you saw the DeLorean
struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you
that I'm alive and well.
"I've been living happily these
past eight months in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt
that hit the DeLorean
"caused a gigawatt
overload
"which scrambled
the time circuits,
"activated
the Flux Capacitor,
"and sent me
back to 1885.
"The overload shorted
out the time circuits
"and destroyed
the flying circuits.
"Unfortunately, the car
will never fly again. "
It actually flew?
Yeah, we had
a hover conversion done
in the early
21st century.
Incredible!
"I set myself up as a
blacksmith as a front
"while I attempted to repair
the damage to the time circuits.
"Unfortunately,
this proved impossible,
"because suitable
replacement parts
"will not be
invented until 1947.
"However,
I've gotten quite adept
"at shoeing horses
and fixing wagons. "
1885! Amazing!
I actually end up as a
blacksmith in the Old West.
Pretty heavy, huh?
"I have buried the DeLorean
in the abandoned Delgado Mine
"adjacent to the old
Boot Hill Cemetery
"as shown on
the enclosed map.
"Hopefully, it should
remain undisturbed
"and preserved until
you uncover it in 1955.
"Inside, you will find
repair instructions.
"My 1955 counterpart... "
That's me.
"... should have no
problem repairing it
"so that you can drive it
back to the future.
"Once you have returned to
1985, destroy the time machine. "
Destroy it?
Yeah. Well, it's
a long story, Doc.
"Do not, I repeat,
do not attempt
"to come back here
to get me.
"I am perfectly happy living in
the fresh air and wide-open spaces.
"And I fear that
unnecessary time travel
"only risks
further disruption
"of the space-time
continuum.
"And please take care
of Einstein for me. "
Einstein?
He's your dog, Doc. Einstein is
what you call your dog in 1985.
"I know you will
give him a good home.
"Remember to
walk him twice a day
"and that he only
likes canned dog food.
"These are my wishes. Please
respect them and follow them.
"And so, Marty, I now say
farewell and wish you Godspeed.
"You've been a good, kind,
and loyal friend to me,
"and you made a real
difference in my life.
"I will always treasure
our relationship
"and think on you
with fond memories,
"warm feelings, and a
special place in my heart.
"Your friend in time,
Doc Emmett L. Brown.
"September 1st, 1885."
I never knew I could
write anything so touching.
I know. I know, Doc.
It's beautiful.
It's all right,
Copernicus.
Everything is
gonna be fine.
I'm sorry, Doc. It's all my
fault you're stuck back there.
I never should've
let Biff get to me.
There are plenty worse places
to be than the Old West.
I could have ended up
in the Dark Ages.
They probably
would have burned me
at the stake as
a heretic or something.
Let's look at the map.
All right, according to
this, the time vehicle
is sealed off
in a side tunnel.
We may have to blast.
Whoa!
I think you woke up
the dead with that blast.
Take this camera. I want
to document everything!
This reminds me
of the time
I attempted to reach
the center of the Earth.
I'd been reading my
favorite author, Jules Verne.
I spent weeks preparing
that expedition.
I didn't even
get this far.
Of course, I was only 12 at the time.
You know, it was the
writings of Jules Verne
that had a profound
effect on my life.
It was when I was 11
that I first read
Twenty Thousand
Leagues Under the Sea.
It was then
that I realized
that I must devote
my life to science.
Doc, check it out.
Look at this.
My initials!
Just like in Journey to
the Center of the Earth!
That means
the time machine
must be right
through this wall!
It's been buried in here for 70
years, two months, and 13 days.
Astounding!
"As you see,
the lightning bolt
"shorted out the time
circuit control microchip.
"The attached... "
Schematic.
"Schematic diagram will allow
you to build a replacement unit
"with 1955 components,
"thus restoring the time machine
to perfect working order. "
Unbelievable that this
little piece of junk
could be
such a big problem.
No wonder this
circuit failed.
It says,
"Made in Japan. "
What do you mean, Doc? All the
best stuff is made in Japan.
Unbelievable!
You know,
when I was a kid,
I always wanted
to be a cowboy.
And now, knowing I'm gonna
spend my future in the past,
it sounds like a wonderful way
to spend my retirement years.
It just occurred to me,
Marty, since I end up in 1885,
perhaps I'm now in
the history books.
I wonder.
Could I go to the
library and look myself up
in the old
newspaper archives?
I don't know, Doc.
You're the one that's
always saying, you know,
it's not good to know too
much about your own destiny.
You're right, Marty.
I know too much already.
Better that I not
attempt to uncover
the circumstances
of my own future.
Copernicus.
Come on, boy!
I'll get him, Doc.
Copernicus!
Copernicus, come on.
Let's go home, boy.
What's wrong?
What's wrong,
Copernicus? Come on.
Come on, let's go home.
Come on. Come on.
Doc! Doc!
Come here!
Quick!
What's wrong, Marty? You
look like you've seen a ghost.
You're not
far off, Doc.
Great Scott!
Check this out.
"Died September 7th,
1885."
That's one week after
you wrote the letter!
"Erected in eternal memory
by his beloved Clara. "
Who the hell
is Clara?
Marty, please
don't stand there!
Oh! Right. Sorry.
I gotta get
another picture.
"Shot in the back by Buford
Tannen over a matter of $80"?
What kind of a future
do you call that?
"Buford Tannen
was a notorious gunman
"whose short temper
and a tendency to drool
"earned him
the nickname Mad Dog.
"He was quick
on the trigger
"and bragged that
he had killed 12 men
"not including
Indians or Chinamen. "
Does it mention me?
Am I one of the 12?
Just a minute.
"However this claim
cannot be substantiated,
"since precise records
were not kept
"after Tannen shot
a newspaper editor
"who printed an unfavorable
story about him in 1884."
That's why
we can't find anything.
Look.
William McFly and family.
Your relatives?
My great-grandfather's
name was William.
That's him.
Good-looking guy.
McFlys, but no Browns.
Well, maybe it was
a mistake, Doc.
Maybe that grave
wasn't yours.
There could've been another
Emmett Brown back in 1885.
No.
I don't know.
Did you have any
relatives here back then?
The Browns didn't come
to Hill Valley until 1908.
And then they
were the von Brauns.
My father changed our name
during the First World War.
Doc, look.
Great Scott, it's me!
Then it is true,
all of it.
It is me who goes back
there and gets shot.
It's not gonna
happen, Doc.
After you fix
the time circuits
and put new tires
on the DeLorean,
I'm going back to 1885,
and I'm bringing you home.
The clothes fit?
Yeah, everything except the
boots, Doc. They're kind of tight.
I don't know. Are you sure
this stuff is authentic?
Of course. Haven't
you ever seen a Western?
Yeah, I have, Doc.
Clint Eastwood never wore
anything like this.
Clint who?
That's right. You
haven't heard of him yet.
Marty, you have
to wear the boots.
You can't wear those
futuristic things back in 1885.
You shouldn't even be
wearing them here in 1955.
All right, Doc. Look,
as soon as I get there,
I'll put them on.
I promise.
Okay. I think
we're about ready.
I put gas in the tank.
Your future clothes
are packed.
Just in case, fresh batteries
for your walkie-talkies.
Oh! What about that
floating device?
Hoverboard.
All right.
You know, Doc, it's gonna
be a hell of a long walk
back to Hill Valley
from here.
It's still
the safest plan.
After all, we can't risk sending
you back into a populated area
or to a spot that's
geographically unknown.
You don't want to
crash into some tree
that once existed
in the past.
This was all
completely open country,
so you'll have plenty of run
out space when you arrive.
Remember, where you're
going, there are no roads.
There's a small cave
over there
which will be a perfect place
to hide the time vehicle.
Well, the new time circuit
control tubes are warmed up.
Time circuits on.
I wrote the letter
on September 1st,
so we'll send you back
the very next day,
September 2nd.
That's a Wednesday.
September 2nd,
1885, 8:00 a. m.
I get shot
on Monday the 7th,
so you have five days
to locate me.
According to my letter,
I'm a blacksmith,
so I probably have
a shop somewhere.
All you have to do is
drive the time vehicle
directly toward
that screen,
accelerating to
88 miles an hour.
Wait a minute. Doc, if I drive
straight towards the screen,
I'm gonna crash
into those Indians.
Marty, you're not thinking
fourth-dimensionally.
You'll instantly be
transported to 1885,
and those Indians
won't even be there.
Right.
Well.
Good luck for
both of our sakes.
See you in the future.
You mean the past.
Exactly.
Happy trails, Marty!
Ready, Marty?
Ready!
Set!
Hi-ho, Silver.
October is inventory time,
so right now, Statler Toyota
is making the best deals of the year
on all 1985-model Toyotas.
You won't find a better car
at a better price with better
service anywhere in Hill Valley.
That's Statler Toyota
in downtown Hill Valley.
The Senate is
expected to vote on this today.
In other news, officials at the
Pacific Nuclear research facility
have denied the rumor that
a case of missing plutonium
was in fact stolen from
their vault two weeks ago.
A Libyan terrorist group
had claimed responsibility
for the alleged theft.
However, officials now attribute
the discrepancy to a
simple clerical error.
The FBI, which is investigating
the matter, had no comment.
Hey, Doc?
Doc?
Hello! Anybody home?
Einstein, come here, boy.
What's going on? Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus!
That is disgusting.
Where the hell is he?
Whoa!
Rock 'n' roll.
Yo. DOC: Marty, is that you?
Hey. Hey, Doc. Where are you?
Thank God I've found you.
Listen, can you meet me at
Twin Pines Mall tonight at 1:15?
I made a major breakthrough,
and I'll need your assistance.
Wait a minute. 1:15 in the morning?
Yeah.
Doc, what's going on?
Where you been all week? Working.
Where's Einstein? Is he with you?
Yeah, he's right here.
You know, Doc, you left
your equipment on all week.
My equipment. That reminds me, Marty.
You better not hook up to the amplifier.
There's a slight
possibility of overload.
Yeah. I'll keep that in mind.
Good. I'll see you
tonight. Don't forget now.
1:15 a.m., Twin Pines Mall.
Right.
Are those my clocks I hear?
Yeah, it's 8:00.
Perfect! My experiment worked!
They're all exactly 25 minutes slow!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you telling me that it's 8:25?
Precisely.
Damn! I'm late for school.
Jennifer. Marty, don't go this way.
Strickland's looking for you.
If you get caught, it'll
be four tardies in a row.
All right, come on. I think we're safe.
You know, this time it wasn't my fault.
The doc set all his
clocks 25 minutes slow.
Doc?
Am I to understand you're still hanging
around with Dr. Emmett Brown, McFly?
Tardy slip for you, Miss Parker.
And one for you, McFly. I
believe that makes four in a row.
Let me give you a nickel's
worth of free advice, young man.
This so-called Dr. Brown is
dangerous. He's a real nutcase.
You hang around with him, you're
gonna end up in big trouble.
Ooh. Yes, sir.
You got a real attitude
problem, McFly. You're a slacker.
You remind me of your
father when he went here.
He was a slacker, too.
Can I go now, Mr. Strickland?
I noticed your band is on the roster
for the dance auditions
after school today.
Why even bother, McFly?
You don't have a chance.
You're too much like your old man.
No McFly ever amounted to anything
in the history of Hill Valley.
Yeah, well, history is gonna change.
Next, please.
Okay, guys, let's rock 'n roll.
All right.
We're the... We're the Pinheads.
One, two, three.
Okay, that's enough. Thank you, fellas.
Hold it, fellas.
I'm afraid you're just too darn loud.
Next, please.
Bring up the next group, please.
Re-elect
Mayor "Goldie" Wilson.
Progress is his middle name.
"Too loud." I can't believe it.
I'm never gonna get a chance
to play in front of anybody.
Marty, one rejection
isn't the end of the world.
I just don't think
I'm cut out for music.
But you're good, Marty.
You're really good,
and this audition
tape of yours is great.
You've gotta send it in
to the record company.
It's like Doc's always
saying. Yeah, I know. I know.
"If you put your mind to it,
"you can accomplish anything."
That's good advice, Marty.
All right, okay, Jennifer.
What if I send in the tape
and they don't like it?
What if they say I'm no good?
What if they say, "Get out of
here, kid. You got no future"?
I mean, I just don't think I
can take that kind of rejection.
Jesus, I'm starting to
sound like my old man.
Come on. He's not that
bad. Save the clock tower.
At least he's letting you
borrow the car tomorrow night.
Check out that 4x4.
That is hot.
Okay. Back her up.
Someday, Jennifer. Someday.
Wouldn't it be great to take
that truck up to the lake?
Throw a couple of
sleeping bags in the back.
Lie out underneath the stars.
Stop it. What?
Does your mom know?
About tomorrow night?
No, get out of town.
My mom thinks I'm going
camping with the guys.
Jennifer, my mother would freak out
if she knew I was
going up there with you,
and I'd get the standard lecture about
how she never did that kind
of stuff when she was a kid.
I mean, look, I think
the woman was born a nun.
She's just trying to
keep you respectable.
Well, she's not doing a very good job.
Terrible.
Save the clock tower.
Mayor Wilson is sponsoring an
initiative to replace that clock.
Thirty years ago, lightning
struck that clock tower
and the clock hasn't run since.
We at the Hill Valley
Preservation Society
think it should be preserved
exactly the way it is
as part of our history and heritage.
There you go, lady. There's a quarter.
Thank you.
Don't forget to take a flyer.
Right.
Save the clock tower!
Where were we?
Right about here.
Jennifer!
It's my dad. I've got to go. Right.
I'll call you tonight.
I'll be at my grandma's.
Here, let me give you the number.
Bye.
Bravo,
Tango, Delta 6-2-9.
Tow for impoundment.
Any unit, please respond.
Perfect. Just perfect.
I can't believe you'd loan me your car
without telling me it had a blind spot.
Blind spot? I could've been killed.
Now, Biff, now, I never noticed
that the car had any blind spot
before when I would drive it.
Hi, Son.
What, are you
blind, McFly? It's there.
How else do you explain
that wreck out there?
Biff, can I assume
that your insurance is
going to pay for the damage?
My insurance? It's your car.
Your insurance should pay for it.
I wanna know who's
going to pay for this?
I spilled beer all over it
when the car smashed into me.
Who's gonna pay my cleaning bill?
Ah...
And where's my reports?
Well, I haven't finished those up yet,
but I figured since
they weren't due till...
Hello? Hello? Anybody home? Huh?
Think, McFly. Think! All right.
I got to have time to get them retyped.
Do you realize what would happen
if I hand in my reports
in your handwriting?
I'll get fired.
You wouldn't want that
to happen, would you?
Would you? Of course not, Biff.
Now, I wouldn't want that to happen.
Now, look. I'll finish
those reports on up tonight,
and I'll run them on over
first thing tomorrow, all right?
Not too early. I sleep in Saturday.
McFly, your shoe's untied.
Oh.
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
Got the place fixed
up nice, though, McFly.
I have your car towed
all the way to your house
and all you got for me is lite beer?
What are you looking at, butthead?
Say hi to your mom for me.
I know what you're going to say, Son,
and you're right. You're right.
But Biff just happens
to be my supervisor,
And I'm afraid I'm just not
very good at confrontations.
But the car, Dad.
I mean, he wrecked it. He totaled it.
I needed that car tomorrow night, Dad.
Do you have any idea how
important this was to me?
Do you have any clue?
I know, and all I can say is, I'm...
I'm sorry.
Believe me, Marty, you're better off
without having to worry
about all the aggravation
and headaches of playing at that dance.
He's absolutely right, Marty.
The last thing you need is headaches.
Kids, we're going to have to
eat this cake by ourselves.
Your Uncle Joey didn't
make parole again.
I think it would be nice if
you all dropped him a line.
Uncle "Jailbird" Joey?
He's your brother, Mom.
Yeah. I think it's a major
embarrassment, having an uncle in prison.
We all make mistakes in life, children.
God damn it. I'm late.
David, watch your mouth!
You come here and kiss your
mother before you go. Come here.
Come on, Mom. Make it
fast. I'll miss my bus.
See you later, Pop.
Time to change that oil.
Hey, Marty. I'm not
your answering service.
While you were outside
pouting over the car,
Jennifer Parker called you twice.
I don't like her, Marty.
Any girl who calls up a boy
is just asking for trouble.
Oh, Mother, there's nothing
wrong with calling a boy.
I think it's terrible.
Girls chasing boys.
When I was your age, I never
chased a boy or called a boy
or sat in a parked car with a boy.
Then how am I supposed
to ever meet anybody?
Well, it'll just happen.
Like the way I met your father.
That was so stupid. Grandpa
hit him with the car.
It was meant to be.
Anyway, if Grandpa hadn't hit him,
then none of you would have been born.
Yeah, well.
I still don't understand
what Dad was doing
in the middle of the street.
What was it, George? Bird-watching?
What, Lorraine? What?
Anyway, your Grandpa
hit him with the car
and brought him into the house.
He seemed so helpless,
like a little lost puppy, and
my heart just went out to him.
Yeah, Mom, we know. You've
told us this story a million times.
You felt sorry for him,
so you decided to go with him
to the Fish Under the Sea dance.
No. It was the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance.
Our first date. I'll never forget it.
It was the night of that terrible
thunderstorm, remember, George?
Your father kissed me for the very
first time on that dance floor.
It was then that I realized
that I was going to spend
the rest of my life with him.
Hello.
Marty, you didn't
fall asleep, did you?
Doc.
No. No, don't be silly.
Listen, this is very important.
I forgot my video camera.
Can you stop by my place and pick
it up on your way to the mall?
Yeah. I'm on my way.
Einstein! Hey, Einstein,
where's the doc, boy? Huh?
Doc!
Marty! You made it!
Yeah.
Welcome to my latest
experiment. This is the big one,
the one I've been
waiting for all my life.
Well, it's a DeLorean...
Bear with me, Marty. All your
questions will be answered.
Roll tape and we'll proceed.
Doc,
is that a DEVO suit?
Never mind that now.
Not now.
All right. I'm ready.
Good evening. I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm standing on the parking
lot at Twin Pines Mall.
It's Saturday morning,
October 26, 1985, 1:18 a.m.,
and this is temporal
experiment number one.
Come on, Einie. Hey,
hey, boy, get in there.
That a boy! In you go. Sit down.
Put your seat belt on. That's it.
Whoa, whoa. Whoa.
Okay.
Please note that Einstein's clock
is in precise synchronization
with my control watch.
Got it? Right. Check, Doc.
Good.
Have a good trip,
Einstein. Watch your head.
You got that thing hooked up to the car?
Watch this.
Yeah. Okay. Got it.
Jesus!
Not me! The car! The car!
If my calculations are correct,
when this baby hits 88 miles per hour
you're going to see some serious shit.
Watch this. Watch this.
What did I tell you?
88 miles per hour!
The temporal displacement occurred
exactly 1:20 a.m. And zero seconds!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ, Doc! You
disintegrated Einstein!
Calm down, Marty. I didn't
disintegrate anything.
The molecular structure of both Einstein
and the car are completely intact.
Then where the hell are they?
The appropriate question is,
"When the hell are they?"
You see, Einstein has just become
the world's first time traveler.
I sent him into the future.
One minute into the future, to be exact.
At precisely 1:21 a.m. And zero seconds,
we shall catch up with
him and the time machine.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you telling me that
you built a time machine
out of a DeLorean?
The way I see it,
if you're going to build
a time machine into a car,
why not do it with some style?
Besides, the stainless-steel
construction made the flux dispersal...
Look out!
What? Is it hot?
It's cold. Damn cold.
Einstein, you little devil!
Einstein's clock is exactly one minute
behind mine and still ticking!
He's all right. He's fine.
And he's completely unaware
that anything happened.
As far as he's concerned,
the trip was instantaneous.
That's why his watch is
exactly one minute behind mine.
He skipped over that minute
to instantly arrive
at this moment in time.
Come here. I'll show you how it works.
All right.
First, you turn the time circuits on.
This readout tells
you where you're going.
This one tells you where you are.
This one tells you where you were.
You input your destination
time on this keypad.
Say you want to see the signing
of the Declaration of Independence.
Or witness the birth of Christ.
Here's a red-letter date
in the history of science.
November 5th, 1955.
Yes, of course. November 5th, 1955.
What? I don't get it. What happened?
That was the day I invented time
travel. I remember it vividly.
I was standing on the edge
of my toilet, hanging a clock.
The porcelain was wet. I slipped,
hit my head on the edge of the sink,
and when I came to, I had a revelation,
a vision, a picture in my
head, a picture of this.
This is what makes time travel
possible. The flux capacitor.
Flux capacitor?
It's taken me almost 30 years
and my entire family fortune
to realize the vision of that day.
My God, has it been that long?
Things have certainly
changed around here.
I remember when this was all farmland
as far as the eye could see.
Old man Peabody owned all of this.
He had this crazy idea
about breeding pine trees.
This is heavy-duty, Doc. This is great.
Does it run on regular
unleaded gasoline?
Unfortunately, no. It requires something
with a little more kick. Plutonium.
Plutonium. Wait a minute.
Are you telling me that
this sucker is nuclear?
Hey, hey, hey! Keep
rolling. Keep rolling there.
No, no, no, this sucker's electrical,
but I need a nuclear reaction
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts
of electricity I need.
Doc, you don't just walk into
a store and buy plutonium.
Did you rip that off?
Of course. From a group
of Libyan nationalists.
They wanted me to build them a bomb,
so I took their plutonium and, in
turn, gave them a shoddy bomb casing
full of used pinball machine parts.
Come on. Let's get you
a radiation suit. Jesus!
We must prepare to reload.
It's safe now. Everything's lead-lined.
Don't you lose those tapes now.
I need that as a record.
Let's put this back here. There we go.
I almost forgot my luggage.
Who knows if they've got
cotton underwear in the future?
I'm allergic to all synthetics.
The future?
That's where you're going?
That's right, 25 years into the future.
I've always dreamed of seeing the
future, looking beyond my years,
seeing the progress of mankind.
Why not?
I'll also be able to see who
wins the next 25 World Series.
Doc.
Huh?
Look me up when you get there.
Indeed, I will. Roll 'em.
I, Dr. Emmett Brown,
am about to embark on
an historic journey.
What am I thinking of?
I almost forgot to
bring extra plutonium.
How did I ever expect to get
back? One pellet, one trip.
I must be out of my mind.
What is it, Einie?
Oh, my God.
They found me. I don't
know how, but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Who? Who?
Who do you think? The Libyans!
Holy shit!
I'll draw their fire!
Doc, wait!
No!
You bastard!
Go! Damn Soviet gun.
Go!
Come on! Move, damn it!
Jesus!
Holy shit!
Let's see if you bastards can do 90.
Crazy drunk driver.
Whoo!
All right. Fred.
You look great. Everything looks great.
1:24. I still got time. I'm coming, Doc!
No! No, not again! Come on! Come on!
Libyans.
No!
You bastard!
Go!
Doc! Doc!
No! No!
You're alive.
Bulletproof vest?
How did you know?
I never got a chance to tell you.
What about all that talk about
screwing up future events?
The space-time continuum?
Well, I figured, what the hell?
So, how far ahead are you going?
About 30 years. It's
a nice, round number.
Look me up when you get there,
all right? Guess I'll be about 47.
I will.
Take care.
You, too.
Right. Bye-bye, Einie.
Oh. And watch that re-entry.
It's a little bumpy.
You bet.
What a nightmare.
If Paul calls me, tell him I'm
working at the boutique late tonight.
Linda, first of all,
I'm not your answering service,
second of all, somebody named Greg
or Craig called you
just a little while ago.
Well, which one was it, Greg or Craig?
I don't know! I can't keep up
with all of your boyfriends.
Hey.
What the hell is this?
Breakfast.
Did you sleep in your
clothes again last night?
Yeah. I...
Yeah. What are you wearing, Dave?
Marty, I always wear
a suit to the office.
You all right? Yeah.
I think we
need a rematch, George.
A rematch?
Why? Were you cheating?
No.
Hello. Good morning.
Mom! Dad!
Did you hit your head?
Marty, are you all right?
You guys look great.
Mom, you look so thin.
Why, thank you, Marty. George!
Good morning, sleepyhead.
Good morning, Dave. Linda.
Good morning, Mom.
Marty, I almost
forgot. Jennifer Parker called.
I sure like her, Marty.
She is such a sweet girl.
Isn't tonight the night of the big date?
What? What, Ma?
Aren't you going up to the lake tonight?
You've been planning it for two weeks.
Mom, we talked about this.
How can I go to the lake?
The car's wrecked.
Wrecked? Wrecked?
When did this happen? Why wasn't I told?
Quiet down.
I'm sure the car is fine.
Why am I always the last
one to know about these things?
See? There's Biff out
there waxing it right now.
Now, Biff, I want to make sure that
we get two coats of wax
this time, not just one.
I'm just finishing up
the second coat now.
Now, Biff, don't con me.
I'm sorry, Mr. McFly.
I meant I was just
starting on the second coat.
Biff. What a character. Always
trying to get away with something.
I've had to stay on top of
Biff ever since high school.
Although, if it wasn't for him...
We never would have fallen in love.
That's right.
Mr. McFly! Mr. McFly, this just arrived.
Oh, hi, Marty. I think
it's your new book.
Honey! Your first novel.
Like I've always told you,
you put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
Oh, Marty, here's your keys.
You're all waxed up, ready for tonight.
Keys?
How about a ride,
mister?
Jennifer.
Oh, man, are you a sight
for sore eyes!
Let me look at you.
Marty, you're acting like
you haven't seen me in a week.
I haven't.
Are you okay?
Is everything all right?
Oh, yeah.
Everything's great.
Marty! You've got to come back with me!
Where?
Back to the future.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing, Doc?
I need fuel.
Go ahead. Quick!
Get in the car.
No, no, no. Look, Doc,
I just got here, okay?
Jennifer's here. We're gonna
take the new truck for a spin.
Well, bring her along.
This concerns her, too.
Wait a minute, Doc. What
are you talking about?
What happens to us
in the future?
What, do we become assholes
or something?
No, no, no. You and
Jennifer both turn out fine.
It's your kids, Marty.
Something has got to
be done about your kids.
Hey, Doc, we better back up. We don't
have enough road to get up to 88.
Roads? Where we're going,
we don't need roads.
Say, Marty!
Marty! Marty, I wanted to
show you these new matchbooks
for my auto detailing
I had printed up.
A flying DeLorean?
What the hell
is going on here?
Did we make it?
Are we back?
We're back.
Let's put her
in the swing.
Then I'll take you home,
and you can come back
in your truck
and wake her.
When she awakens here in
her own house and it's dark,
you should be able to convince
her that it was all a dream.
Wait a minute.
We're just gonna
leave her here
on the porch?
The disorientation will help
convince her that it was all a dream.
How long do you think
she's gonna be out?
I'm not quite sure. She
received quite a shock.
Could be for
a few minutes.
Most probably,
a couple of hours.
You better bring smelling
salts back with you.
You're the doc, Doc.
All right. Come on.
Let's go, Einie.
Don't worry.
She'll be fine.
I don't remember bars
being on these windows.
If you need me, I'll be back at
my lab dismantling this thing.
Right.
What the hell?
Hey. Hey, wait.
Wait a minute.
What are
you doing in my room?
Help! Rape! Mom!
Okay. Okay.
Dad, help!
Freeze, sucker!
He jumped me! Hey, it's okay.
I don't want any trouble.
He came through
the window!
You got trouble now,
you piece of trash.
What are you doing in here
with my daughter?
Hey, listen, I'm just
in the wrong house.
You got that right,
you little son of a...
Hey, look,
I made a mistake.
Damn right you
made a mistake!
Kill him!
I'm gonna tear
your ass up!
That's right.
You keep running, sucker!
And you tell
that realty company
that I ain't selling!
You hear?
We ain't gonna
be terrorized!
This has gotta
be the wrong year.
1985?
It can't be.
Drop it.
So you're the son of a bitch
who's been stealing my newspapers.
Mr. Strickland.
Mr. Strickland. It's
me, sir. It's Marty.
Who?
It's Marty McFly.
Marty McFly.
Don't you know me, sir?
From school, sir.
I've never seen you
before in my life,
but you look to
me like a slacker.
Yeah, that's right. That's
right. I am a slacker.
Don't you remember? You
gave me detention last week.
Last week? The school
burned down six years ago.
Now, you got
exactly three seconds
to get off my porch
with your nuts intact.
One.
Please, Mr. Strickland,
I just want to know what
the hell's going on here.
Two.
Hey, Strickland!
Yeah!
Eat lead, slackers!
Watch where you're going,
crazy drunk pedestrian.
Red.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the Biff Tannen Museum.
Dedicated to Hill Valley's
number one citizen
and America's
greatest living folk hero,
the one and only
Biff Tannen.
Of course, we've all heard
the legend, but who is the man?
Inside, you will learn
how Biff Tannen became
one of the richest
and most powerful men
in America.
Learn the amazing history
of the Tannen family,
starting with his great-grandfather,
Buford "Mad Dog" Tannen,
fastest gun in the West.
See Biff's
humble beginnings
and how a trip
to the racetrack
on his 21 st birthday made
him a millionaire overnight.
Share in the excitement
of a fabulous winning streak
that earned him the nickname
"The Luckiest Man on Earth. "
Learn how Biff parlayed
that lucky winning streak
into the vast empire
called Biffco.
Discover how in 1979, Biff successfully
lobbied to legalize gambling
and turned Hill Valley's
dilapidated courthouse
into a beautiful
casino hotel.
I just want to say one
thing. God bless America!
Meet the women
who shared in his passion
as he searched
for true love,
and relive
Biff's happiest moment
as, in 1973, he realized
his life-long romantic dream
by marrying his high school
sweetheart, Lorraine Baines McFly.
How's it feel,
Mr. Tannen?
Third time's
the charm.
No! No!
Hey, you're coming
with us upstairs.
Let me go.
Look, sonny, we can do this
the easy way or the hard way.
The easy way.
Mom? Mom, is that you?
Just relax, Marty.
You've been asleep
for almost two hours.
I had a horrible nightmare.
It was terrible.
Well, you're safe
and sound now,
back on the good
old 27th floor.
Twenty-seventh floor!
Mom?
Mom, that can't be you.
Well, yes, it's me,
Marty. Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm fine. It's just
that you're so... You're so
big.
Oh. Everything's gonna be
fine, Marty. Are you hungry?
I can call room service.
Room service?
Lorraine!
Oh, my God.
It's your father.
My father?
You're supposed to be in Switzerland,
you little son of a bitch!
My father!
Did you get kicked out
of another boarding school?
Damn it, Lorraine. Do you know
how much perfectly good dough
I've blown on this
no-good kid of yours, huh?
On all three of them?
What the hell do you
care? We can afford it.
The least we can do
with all that money
is provide a better life
for our children.
Hold on one second.
Let's get this straight.
Marty is your kid, not mine.
And all the money
in the world
wouldn't do jack shit
for that lazy bum.
Stop it, Biff.
Just stop it.
Look at him. He's a butthead,
just like his old man was.
Don't you dare speak
that way about George.
You're not even
half the man he was.
You son of a bitch!
Hey.
Always
the little hothead, huh?
You wanna
take a poke at me?
Damn it, Biff.
That's it. I'm leaving.
So go ahead. But think
about this, Lorraine!
Who's gonna pay for
all your clothes, huh?
And your jewelry
and your liquor?
Who's gonna pay for your
cosmetic surgery, Lorraine?
You were the one who wanted
me to get these things.
If you want them back,
you can have them.
Look, Lorraine.
You walk out that door,
and I won't only cut off
you. I'll cut off your kids.
You wouldn't.
Wouldn't I?
First your daughter,
Linda.
I'll cancel all
her credit cards.
She can settle her debts
with the bank all by herself.
Your idiot son, Dave. I'll
get his probation revoked.
And as for Marty.
Well, maybe you'd like to have
all three of your kids behind bars,
just like
your brother Joey.
One big, happy,
jailbird family.
All right, Biff.
You win. I'll stay.
As for you, I'll be back up here
in an hour, so you better not be.
He was right,
and I was wrong.
Mom!
Mom,
what are you saying?
You're actually
defending him.
I had it coming.
He's my husband,
and he takes care
of all of us,
and he deserves
our respect.
Respect?
Your husband! How could
he be your husband?
How could you
leave Dad for him?
Leave Dad?
Marty, are you
feeling all right?
No. No, I'm not
feeling all right!
I don't understand one damn
thing that's going on around here,
and why nobody can give me
a simple, straight answer.
Oh, they must have hit you
over the head hard this time.
Mom, I just want
to know one thing.
Where's my father?
Where's George McFly?
Marty, George,
your father
is in the same place he's
been for the past 12 years.
Oak Park Cemetery.
No.
No! This can't
be happening!
"March 15, 1973."
No! Please, God, no!
No, please, God.
Please, God, no.
This can't be happening.
This can't be...
I'm afraid it is
happening, Marty. All of it.
Doc!
When I learned
about your father,
I figured
you'd come here.
Then you know
what happened to him?
Do you know what
happened March 15, 1973?
Yes, Marty. I know.
I went
to the public library
to try to make sense
out of all the madness.
The place was
boarded up, shut down,
so I broke in and
borrowed some newspapers.
I don't get it, Doc.
I mean, how can all
this be happening?
It's like we're in
hell or something.
No, it's Hill Valley. Although, I
can't imagine hell being much worse.
Oh, Einie.
I'm sorry, boy.
The lab is an awful,
awful, awful, awful mess.
Attaboy.
Obviously, the time
continuum has been disrupted,
creating this new
temporal event sequence
resulting in this
alternate reality.
English, Doc.
Here, here, here.
Let me illustrate.
Imagine that this line
represents time.
Here's the present, 1985,
the future and the past.
Prior to this point in
time, somewhere in the past,
the timeline skewed
into this tangent
creating
an alternate 1985.
Alternate to you,
me and Einstein,
but reality for
everyone else.
Recognize this?
It's the bag
the sports book came in.
I know, because the
receipt was still inside.
I found them in the time
machine along with this.
It's the top
of Biff's cane.
I mean,
Old Biff from the future.
Correct. It was
in the time machine
because Biff was in the time
machine with the sports almanac.
Holy shit.
You see, while we were in the future,
Biff got
the sports book,
stole the time machine,
went back in time,
and gave the book to himself
at some point in the past.
Look. It says right here
that Biff made
his first million
betting on a horse race
in 1958.
He wasn't just lucky.
He knew because he had all the
race results in the sports almanac.
That's how he made
his entire fortune.
Look at his pocket
with a magnifying glass.
The almanac.
Son of a bitch
stole my idea.
He must have been
listening when I...
It's my fault. The
whole thing is my fault.
If I hadn't bought
that damn book,
none of this would
have ever happened.
Well, it's all
in the past.
You mean the future?
Whatever.
It demonstrates precisely
how time travel
can be misused
and why the time machine
must be destroyed
after we straighten
all of this out.
Right. So we go
back to the future,
and we stop Biff from
stealing the time machine.
We can't,
because if we travel
into the future from
this point in time,
it will be the future
of this reality,
in which Biff is
corrupt and powerful
and married
to your mother
and in which this
has happened to me.
No. Our only chance to repair
the present is in the past
at the point where the timeline
skewed into this tangent.
In order to put the universe
back as we remember it
and get back
to our reality,
we have to find
out the exact date
and the specific
circumstances
of how, where
and when Young Biff
got his hands on
that sports almanac.
I'll ask him.
Bulletproof vest! Great
flick! Great frigging flick!
The guy is brilliant.
Hey, what the hell's
going...
Hey! What the hell
are you doing in here?
Party's over, Biff.
Sorry, ladies.
How did you get past
my security downstairs?
There's a little matter
we need to talk about.
Yeah. Money, right?
Well, forget it.
No. Not money.
Gray's Sports Almanac.
You heard him, girls.
Party's over.
Start talking, kid. What
else you know about that book?
First, you tell me
how you got it.
How, where and when.
All right.
Take a seat.
Sit down!
November 12, 1955.
That was when.
November 12, 1955. That
was the date I went back...
That was the date of the famous
Hill Valley lightning storm.
You know your history.
Very good.
I'll never forget
that Saturday.
I'd just picked
my car up from the shop,
'cause I'd rolled it in a
drag race a few days earlier.
I thought you crashed
into a manure truck.
How do you know
about that?
My father told me
about it.
Your father?
Before he died.
Yeah. Right.
So there I was,
minding my own business.
This crazy old codger
with a cane shows up.
He says he's my
distant relative.
I don't see
any resemblance.
So he says, "How would
you like to be rich?"
So I said, "Sure. "
So he lays
this book on me.
He says this book
will tell me the outcome
of every sporting event
till the end of the century.
All I have to do is bet on the
winner, and I'll never lose.
So I said,
"What's the catch?"
He says, "No catch.
Just keep it a secret. "
After that,
he disappeared.
I never saw him again.
Oh, and he told me
one more thing.
He said, "Someday a
crazy, wild-eyed scientist,
"or a kid may show up
asking about that book.
"And if that
ever happens... "
Funny. I never
thought it would be you.
Yeah, well, Biff, you're
forgetting one thing.
What the hell is that?
You're dead,
you little son of a bitch!
Hey, there he is!
Hey, hey!
Oh, yeah!
Go ahead, kid. Jump.
A suicide will
be nice and neat.
What if I don't?
Lead poisoning.
What about
the police, Biff?
They're gonna match up
the bullet with that gun.
Kid, I own the police.
Besides,
they couldn't match up
the bullet that
killed your old man.
You son of a...
I suppose it's
poetic justice.
Two McFlys
with the same gun.
Idiot.
What the hell?
Nice shot, Doc!
You're not
gonna believe this.
We gotta
go back to 1955.
I don't believe it.
That's right, Doc.
November 12, 1955.
Unbelievable that Old Biff could've
chosen that particular date.
It could mean that
that point in time
inherently contains some
sort of cosmic significance,
almost as if it were
the temporal junction point
for the entire
space-time continuum.
On the other hand, it could
just be an amazing coincidence.
Damn!
Got to fix that thing.
All right.
Time circuits on.
What do you mean,
time circuits on?
Doc, we're not
going back now.
Yep.
Doc, what about Jennifer?
What about Einstein?
We can't just
leave them here.
Don't worry, Marty. Assuming
we succeed in our mission,
this alternate 1985 will be
changed back into the real 1985,
instantaneously transforming
around Jennifer and Einie.
Jennifer and Einie
will be fine,
and they will have absolutely
no memory of this horrible place.
Doc.
What if we don't succeed?
We must succeed.
Well, Doc,
it's destroyed.
Just like you wanted.
Hey, butthead,
get away...
Watch it, Biff!
Marty, I didn't mean
to scare you.
I didn't recognize you
in those clothes.
What the hell
are you doing?
Just putting on
the second coat now.
You going cowboy, huh?
Come on, guys. We're
gonna be late for brunch.
Coming, Dave.
Come on, Dad,
we're not gonna hold
your reservations
all day.
I can't
find my glasses.
Lorraine, have you seen my glasses?
They're in your
suede jacket, honey.
Marty, what's wrong? We
thought you went to the lake.
You wore that
to the lake?
Thank God you guys
are all back to normal.
Marty, who are you supposed
to be? Clint Eastwood?
Right.
I gotta go get Jennifer.
I really like
that hat, Marty.
Thanks, Biff.
Jennifer.
Jen.
Marty.
I had the worst
nightmare.
Marty, that dream
I had is so real.
It was about
the future.
About us.
And you got fired.
Wait a minute. What do
you mean I got fired?
"Hilldale. "
Hilldale!
This is where we live.
I mean, this is where
we're going to live.
Someday.
Marty, it was a dream,
wasn't it?
Hey.
The big M.
How's it hanging, McFly?
Hey, Needles.
Nice set of wheels.
Let's see what she can do.
Next green light.
No, thanks.
What's the matter?
Chicken?
Chicken McFly.
Whoo!
Marty, don't.
Grab hold of something.
Come on!
Get on!
Yeah, go! Go, go, go!
Did you
do that on purpose?
Yeah, you think I'm stupid
enough to race that asshole?
Jeez! I would have
hit that Rolls-Royce.
It erased.
You're right. There's not much left.
Doc's never
coming back.
I'm sure gonna
miss him, Jen.
What the hell?
Doc!
Marty!
Doc! Doc!
Marty,
it runs on steam!
Meet the family.
Clara, you know.
Hi, Marty!
Ma'am!
These are our boys.
Jules and Verne.
Boys, this is Marty and Jennifer.
Doc, I thought I'd
never see you again.
You can't keep
a good scientist down.
After all, I had to
come back for Einstein,
and, well, I didn't want
you to be worried about me.
Oh!
I brought you
a little souvenir.
It's great, Doc.
Thanks.
Dr. Brown, I brought this
note back from the future,
and now it's erased.
Of course
it's erased.
But what does
that mean?
It means your future
hasn't been written yet.
No one's has.
Your future is
whatever you make it.
So make it a good one,
both of you.
We will, Doc!
Stand back!
All right, boys,
buckle up!
Hey, Doc, where are you
going now? Back to the future?
No, already been there.
What the hell
was that?
Taxicab.
What do you mean a "taxicab"?
I thought we were flying.
Precisely.
All right, Doc.
What's going on, huh?
Where are we?
When are we?
We're descending toward
Hill Valley, California,
at 4:29 p. m. On Wednesday,
October 21, 2015.
2015?
You mean
we're in the future.
Future.
Marty, what do you mean?
How can we be
in the future?
Jennifer...
I don't know how
to tell you this,
but you're
in a time machine.
And this is
the year 2015?
October 21, 2015.
God, so, like,
you weren't kidding.
Marty, we can
actually see our future.
Doc, now, you said
we were married, right?
Yeah...
Yeah?
Was it a big wedding?
Marty, we're gonna be able
to see our wedding.
Wow. I'm gonna be able
to see my wedding dress.
Wow.
God, I wonder
where we live.
I bet it's a big house
with lots of kids.
How many kids...
Doc! What the hell
are you doing?
Relax, Marty.
It's just a sleep-inducing
alpha rhythm generator.
She was asking
too many questions,
and no one should know too
much about their future.
This way
when she wakes up,
she'll think it
was all a dream.
Then what did
you bring her for?
I had to do something.
She saw the time machine. I couldn't just
leave her there with that information.
Don't worry. She's not
essential to my plan.
Well, you're the doc,
Doc.
Here's our exit.
First, you've gotta get
out and change clothes.
Right now?
It's pouring rain.
Wait five more seconds.
Right on the tick.
Amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
Too bad the post office isn't as
efficient as the weather service.
Excuse the disguise,
Marty,
but I was afraid you
wouldn't recognize me.
I went to
a rejuvenation clinic
and got
an all-natural overhaul.
They took out some wrinkles, did
a hair repair, changed the blood,
added a good 30 or
40 years to my life.
They also replaced my spleen
and colon. What do you think?
You look great, Doc.
The future.
Unbelievable.
I gotta
check this out, Doc.
All in good time, Marty.
We're on a tight
schedule here.
Tell me about my future.
I mean, I know I make it big.
But what? Do I become,
like, a rich rock star?
Please, Marty, no one should know
too much about their own destiny.
Right. Right.
I am rich, though, right?
Marty, please,
take off your shirt.
Put on the jacket
and the shoes.
Got a mission
to accomplish.
Ah-ha.
Precisely on schedule.
Power laces.
All right.
This thing doesn't fit.
Size-adjusting fit.
Pull out
your pants pockets.
All kids in the future
wear their pants inside out.
Put on this cap.
Perfect. You're the spitting
image of your future son.
What?
Help me move
Jennifer over here.
So what's the deal?
Grab her feet.
All right.
Okay, now what?
In exactly two minutes, you go
around the corner into the Cafe '80s.
Cafe '80s?
It's one of those nostalgia
places, but not done very well.
Go in and order a Pepsi.
Here's a 50.
Then wait for
a guy named Griff.
Right. Griff.
Right.
Griff's going to ask you about
tonight. Are you in or out?
Tell him you are out.
Whatever he says,
whatever happens,
say no,
you're not interested.
Okay.
Then leave, come back
here and wait for me.
Don't talk to anyone, don't
touch anything, don't do anything,
don't interact
with anyone
and try not to
look at anything.
I don't get it.
I thought you said
this had something
to do with my kids.
Look what happens
to your son.
My son?
God, he looks
just like me.
"Within two hours of his
arrest, Martin McFly Jr
"was tried,
convicted and sentenced
"to 15 years in
a state penitentiary. "
Within two hours?
The justice system works
swiftly in the future
now that they've
abolished all lawyers.
Oh, this is heavy.
It gets worse.
Next week, your daughter
attempts to break him
out of jail,
and she gets sent up
for 20 years.
My daughter. Wait a
minute. I have a daughter?
You see? This one event
starts a chain reaction
that completely destroys
your entire family.
Hey, Doc, this date...
This is tomorrow's newspaper.
Precisely, I already went
further ahead into time
to see
what else happens.
I backtracked everything
to this one event.
That's why
we're here today,
to prevent this incident
from ever happening.
Damn! I'm late!
Wait a minute.
Where you going now?
To intercept
the real Marty Jr.
You're taking his place. Around
the corner at the Cafe '80s.
Guy named Griff.
Just say no!
Hey, what about Jennifer? We're
not just gonna leave her here.
Don't worry,
she'll be safe.
It'll just be
for a few minutes.
And, Marty, be careful
around that Griff character.
He's got a few short circuits
in his bionic implants.
The future.
Welcome to Texaco.
You can trust your car
to the system with the star.
Checking oil.
Checking landing gear.
The shark
still looks fake.
Hi, friends.
Goldie Wilson III
for Wilson Hover
Conversion Systems.
You know, when my grandpa
was mayor of Hill Valley,
he had to worry
about traffic problems.
But now, you don't have
to worry about traffic.
I'll hover-convert
your old road car
into a skyway flier
for only $39,999.95.
So come on down and see me,
Goldie Wilson III,
at any one of our 29
convenient locations.
Remember,
keep 'em flying.
It's got a hot salsa,
avocados,
cilantro mixed with
your choice of beans,
chicken, beef or pork.
Waiter. Waiter.
Welcome to the Cafe '80s,
where it's always morning in
America, even in the afternoon.
Our special today is
mesquite-grilled sushi.
You must have the hostage
special! Cajun style.
You must have
the hostage special!
Hey, hey, hey, guys!
Hey, hey, guys!
All I want is a Pepsi.
Hey, McFly!
Yeah.
I've seen you around.
You're Marty McFly's kid,
aren't you?
Biff?
You're Marty Jr.
Tough break, kid.
Must be rough being named
after a complete butthead.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Hello? Hello?
Anybody home?
Hey. Hey.
Think, McFly, think!
Your old man?
Mr. Loser?
What?
That's right.
Loser with a capital "L."
Look, I happen to know George
McFly is no longer a loser.
No, I'm not talking
about George McFly.
I'm talking
about his kid.
Your old man,
Marty McFly Sr.,
the man who
took his life
and flushed it
completely down the toilet.
I did?
I mean...
I mean, he did?
Hey, Gramps,
I told you two coats of
wax on my car, not just one!
Hey, hey, I just put the
second coat on last week.
Yeah?
With your eyes closed?
Are you two related?
Hello? Hello?
Anybody home?
What do you think, Griff just
calls me "Grandpa" for his health?
He's Griff?
Gramps!
What the hell
am I paying you for?
Hey, kid, say hello
to your grandma for me.
Get out here, Gramps.
Hey, take it easy!
And, McFly, don't go
anywhere! You're next!
This is a video game.
I got it working.
My dad taught me
about these.
It is Wild Gunman.
How do you play
this thing?
I'll show you, kid.
I'm a crack shot at this.
You mean you have
to use your hands?
That's like
a baby's toy.
Baby's toy?
Pepsi Perfect.
Damn!
Pepsi.
Hey, McFly!
I thought I told you
to stay in here!
Griff. Guys,
how's it going?
McFly!
Yeah?
What?
Your shoe's unvelked.
So, McFly, have you made a decision
about tonight's opportunity?
Yeah, Griff. You know, I was
thinking about it. I'm not sure,
because I just think,
you know,
it might be a little
bit dangerous, so...
What's wrong, McFly?
You got no scrote?
He's a complete wimp.
What's it gonna be, McFly?
Are you in or out?
I just... I'm not sure
that I should.
You know, because I think that I
should discuss it with my father.
Your father?
Wrong answer, McFly!
You lose!
Okay, Griff, I'll do it. I'll
do it, buddy. Whatever you say.
Stay down and shut up.
Keep pedaling,
you two!
Now, let's hear
the right answer.
Well!
Since when did you become
the physical type?
The answer's no, Griff.
No?
Yeah. What are you,
deaf and stupid?
I said no!
What's wrong, McFly?
Chicken?
What did you
call me, Griff?
Chicken, McFly!
Nobody calls me
chicken.
All right, punk!
Hey, look!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Stop! Little girl,
little girl. Stop.
Hey.
Look,
I need to borrow
your Hoverboard.
Where is he?
Here.
There!
He's on a Hoverboard.
Get the boards!
Get McFly!
Get him!
Yeah!
Yeah, we got him!
There's something very
familiar about all this.
Hey, McFly, you bojo!
Those boards
don't work on water!
Unless you've
got power!
Hook on!
Batter up!
Holy shit!
Buttheads.
Drying mode on.
Jacket drying.
Your jacket is now dry.
Hey, kid.
Hey, little girl, thanks.
Keep it.
I got a Pit Bull now.
Come on. Let's go.
Save the clock tower!
Hey, kid.
Throw in 100 bucks, will you,
and help save
the clock tower.
Sorry, no.
Come on, kid.
That's an important
historical landmark!
Look, some other time.
Lightning struck
that thing 60 years ago.
Wait a minute.
Cubs win World Series.
Against Miami?
Yeah, it's something, huh?
Who would've thought?
100-1 shot!
I wish I could go back to
the beginning of the season,
put some money
on the Cubs.
I just meant
that Miami...
What did you just say?
I said I wish I could go back
to the beginning of the season.
Put some money
on the Cubbies!
Now this has an interesting
feature. It has a dust jacket.
Books used to have these
to protect the covers.
Of course, that was before
they had dust-repellent paper.
Ah.
And if you're
interested in dust,
we have a quaint little
piece from the 1980s.
It's called a DustBuster.
I can't lose.
Marty! Marty! Up here!
Hey, Doc,
what's going on?
Stand by.
I'll park over there.
Yeah, all right.
Hey, right on time.
Flying DeLorean.
I haven't seen one
of those in 30 years.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Sorry.
Hey, I'm walking here!
I'm walking here!
What the hell?
Don't drive, trank,
low-res scuzzball!
Two of them?
I left him in a suspended
animation kennel.
Einstein never
knew I was gone!
Marty! What in the name of Sir
Isaac H. Newton happened here?
Oh, yeah, Doc, listen, my kid
showed up. All hell broke loose.
Your kid?
Great Scott, the sleep
inducer. I was afraid of this.
Because I used it
on Jennifer,
there wasn't
enough power left
to knock your son out
for a full hour. Damn!
Doc, Doc, Doc,
look at this!
It's changing.
I was framed!
Yes! Yes, of course!
Because this Hoverboard
incident has now occurred,
Griff now goes to jail.
Therefore, your son
won't go with him tonight,
and that robbery
will never take place.
Thus, history,
future history,
has now been altered,
and this is the proof!
Marty, we've succeeded, not
exactly as I planned, but no matter.
Let's go get Jennifer
and go home!
Hi, Einie. Hi, buddy.
What's this?
It's a souvenir.
"50 years of
sports statistics. "
Hardly recreational
reading material, Marty.
Well, hey, Doc,
what's the harm
in bringing back a
little info on the future?
You know, maybe we could
place a couple bets.
Marty, I didn't invent the
time machine for financial gain!
The intent here is to gain a
clearer perception of humanity.
Where we've been,
where we're going,
the pitfalls and the possibilities,
the perils and the promise.
Perhaps even an answer to
that universal question, "Why?"
Hey, Doc,
I'm all for that.
What's wrong with making
a few bucks on the side?
I am going to put
this in the trash.
Great Scott!
McFly, Jennifer Jane
Parker, 3793 Oakhurst Street,
Hilldale, age 47.
Forty-seven? That's a
hell of a good face-lift.
What the hell are
they doing, Doc?
They used her thumbprint
to assess her ID.
Since her thumbprint never
changes over the years,
they simply assume she's
the Jennifer of the future.
Well, we gotta stop them.
What are we gonna say?
That we're time travelers?
They'd have us committed.
She's clean. That
means we take her home.
Home? To Hilldale?
Lt'll be dark by the
time we get out there.
That's it. They're taking
her home to your future home!
We'll arrive
shortly thereafter,
get her out of there
and go back to 1985.
You mean I'm gonna
see where I live?
I'm gonna see myself
as an old man?
No, no, no, Marty. That could
result in... Great Scott!
Jennifer could conceivably
encounter her future self!
The consequences of that
could be disastrous!
Doc, what do you mean?
I foresee
two possibilities.
One, coming face to face
with herself 30 years older
would put her into shock,
and she'd simply pass out,
or two, the encounter
could create a time paradox,
the results of which could cause
a chain reaction that would unravel
the very fabric of
the space-time continuum
and destroy
the entire universe!
Granted, that's
a worst-case scenario.
The destruction might,
in fact, be very localized,
limited to
merely our own galaxy.
Well, that's a relief.
Let's go. I sure hope we find
Jennifer before she finds herself.
The skyway's jammed. It's gonna
take us forever to get there.
And this stays here.
I didn't invent the time
machine to win at gambling.
I invented a time machine
to travel through time!
I know. I know.
I know, Doc.
So, Doc Brown
invented a time machine.
Hilldale.
Nothing but a breeding ground
for tranks, lobos and zipheads.
Yeah, they ought to tear
this whole place down.
Welcome home, Jennifer.
Whoa!
You all right?
Yeah.
You got a little tranked,
but I think you can walk.
Ma'am,
you should reprogram.
It's dangerous to
enter without lights on.
Lights on?
Yes. Now, look.
Just take it easy
and you'll be fine.
And be careful
in the future.
The future?
Have a nice day,
Mrs. McFly.
Broadcasting beautiful views
24 hours a day,
you're tuned to
the Scenery Channel.
I'm in the future.
I get married in
the Chapel O Love?
Mom?
Mom, is that you?
I gotta get
out of here!
Mom!
Mom? Mom, is that you?
Grandma Lorraine!
Sweetheart!
Hi!
What happened
to Grandpa?
Oh, he threw
his back out again.
How's Granddad's
little pumpkin?
How did you do that?
How did he do that?
Oh, out on the
golf course.
Are your folks home yet?
I brought pizza
for everyone.
Oh, who's going
to eat all that?
Oh, I will.
Damn this traffic!
Jennifer, that is Old Jennifer,
usually gets home around now.
I hope we're
not too late.
What is it?
What's the matter, Doc?
For a moment, I thought I
saw a taxi in my rear display.
I thought it was
following us. Weird.
I can't believe this
window's still broken.
Well, when the scenescreen
repairman called Daddy a chicken,
Daddy threw him
out of the house.
Now, we can't get
anybody to fix it.
Oh, look how
worn out this is.
Your father's
biggest problem, Marlene,
is that he loses
all self-control
when someone
calls him chicken.
How many times have
we heard it, George?
"Mom, I can't let them
think I'm chicken. "
"Can't let them
You're right.
Well, you're right!
About 30 years ago,
your father tried to
prove he wasn't chicken,
and he ended up in
an automobile accident.
Oh, you mean with
the Rolls-Royce?
Automobile accident.
All right, Einie,
let's find Jennifer.
I don't believe it.
I live in Hilldale?
This is great!
Way to go, McFly.
Marty, stay here.
Just change clothes.
If I need you,
I'll holler.
Come on, Doc, I wanna
check out my house.
We can't risk you running
into your older self.
Come on, Einie,
let's go.
Where's Jennifer?
Hilldale.
This is bitching.
One, seven,
four point five zero.
That will be $174.50.
Here.
I'd be careful, old timer.
This is a rough neighborhood.
Where's my receipt?
Right here. Here it is.
Hello. Hello.
How about a tip?
That accident caused
a chain reaction
that sent Marty's life
straight down the tubes.
If not for that accident,
your father's life
would have turned out
very differently.
The man in the Rolls-Royce
wouldn't have pressed charges,
Marty wouldn't
have broken his hand,
and he wouldn't have
given up on his music,
and he wouldn't have spent all those
years feeling sorry for himself.
Hey, Mom, nice pants.
I think the real reason your
mother married him was because
she felt sorry for him.
"Mom"?
Such a sweet girl.
Art off. I think maybe she deserves...
Okay, I want channels 18, 24, 63,
109, 87 and the Weather Channel.
The Weather Channel,
bringing you
the world's weather
24 hours a day.
Weather conditions
remain the same...
All board-certified
implant surgeons...
With a minor warm front...
Welcome home, Marty.
Hey, hey, hey.
Dad's home.
That's right. He's home. Dad's home.
Lord of the manor.
Hello. Hello.
King of the castle.
Hello.
What the hell is this?
Lithium mode on.
Yeah. That's better.
Damned kids.
The best...
Hey, Son.
Watching a little TV
for a change?
Son of a...
Hey, pizza.
I'm hungry.
All right.
Just wait your turn.
Grandma,
when it's ready,
could you just
shove it in my mouth?
Don't you be a smartass.
Oh, great!
The Atrocity Channel.
Hydrate level 4, please.
Mmm.
Is it ready?
Here you go.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Mom, you sure
can hydrate a pizza.
I'm sorry. I missed
that whole thing.
Well, I'm just worried about
Jennifer. Why isn't she home yet?
I'm not sure
where Jennifer is, Mom.
She should have
been home hours ago.
I'm having a hard time keeping
track of her these days.
Hey, fruit.
Fruit, please. Thank you.
She's in one of those
moods, I guess. I don't know.
Aren't you and Jennifer
getting along?
Oh, yeah.
Great, Mom.
We're more like a couple
of teenagers, you know.
Dad, telephone.
It's Needles.
Dad, it's for you.
All right. Well, I'll take
that in the den. Excuse me.
Retract.
Hello.
I'm in here, please.
Hey, the big M.
How's it hanging, McFly?
Hey, Needles.
Needles?
So, did you take look at that
little business proposal of mine?
I don't know, Needles.
What are
you afraid of?
If this thing works, it'll solve
all your financial problems.
And if it doesn't work,
Needles, I could get fired.
It's illegal. I mean, what if
the Jits is monitoring, huh?
The Jits will
never find out.
Oh, God.
Come on. Stick your card in
the slot, and I'll handle it.
Unless you want everyone in the
division to think you're chicken.
Nobody calls me chicken,
Needles.
Nobody!
All right.
Prove it.
All right, Needles.
Here's my card.
Scan it. I'm in.
Thanks, McFly. I'll see
you at the plant tomorrow.
Chicken.
McFly!
McFly, I was monitoring that
scan you just interfaced.
You are terminated!
Terminated. No!
No! It wasn't my fault,
sir. It was Needles.
Needles was
behind the whole thing.
And you cooperated.
No, I didn't. It was a sting
operation. It was illegal.
I was setting him up.
And you knew.
McFly, read my fax!
No! Please, no. I cannot
be fired. I'm fired.
Oh, this is heavy.
What am I going
to tell Jennifer?
Jennifer. Jennifer.
Oh, Doc, am I glad
to see you.
Go out the front door.
I'll meet you there.
But it doesn't open.
There's no doorknob.
Press your thumb
to the plate.
What plate?
Marty, what does
this fax mean?
Oh, Mom, it's a joke, an
office joke. Kind of a joke fax.
Marty, I heard you yelling.
Mom, Mom, Mom,
calm down.
I wasn't yelling. Needles and
I were just kind of joking.
Welcome home, Jennifer.
Marty,
have you lost your job?
Lost my job, Mom? Get out
of town. Look, you know...
I'm young!
I'm old!
Marty! Marty!
Marty, come quick!
Quick!
She encountered
her older self
and went into shock,
just as I predicted.
She'll be fine.
Let's get her back
to 1985,
and then I'm gonna destroy
the time machine.
Destroy it?
What about that
stuff about humanity,
where we're going
and why?
The risks are just too great,
as this incident proves.
And I was
behaving responsibly.
You can imagine
the danger
if the time machine were to
fall into the wrong hands.
My only regret is that
I'll never get a chance
to visit my favorite
historical era,
the Old West.
But time traveling
is just too dangerous.
Better that I devote
myself to studying
the other great mystery
of the universe,
women.
Marty, Einie, brace yourselves
for temporal displacement.
Did we make it?
Are we back?
We're back.
Let's put her
in the swing.
Then I'll take you home,
and you can come back
in your truck
and wake her.
When she awakens here in
her own house and it's dark,
you should be able to convince
her that it was all a dream.
Wait a minute.
We're just gonna
leave her here
on the porch?
The disorientation will help
convince her that it was all a dream.
How long do you think
she's gonna be out?
I'm not quite sure. She
received quite a shock.
Could be for
a few minutes.
Most probably,
a couple of hours.
You better bring smelling
salts back with you.
You're the doc, Doc.
All right. Come on.
Let's go, Einie.
Don't worry.
She'll be fine.
I don't remember bars
being on these windows.
If you need me, I'll be back at
my lab dismantling this thing.
Right.
What the hell?
Hey. Hey, wait.
Wait a minute.
What are
you doing in my room?
Help! Rape! Mom!
Okay. Okay.
Dad, help!
Freeze, sucker!
He jumped me! Hey, it's okay.
I don't want any trouble.
He came through
the window!
You got trouble now,
you piece of trash.
What are you doing in here
with my daughter?
Hey, listen, I'm just
in the wrong house.
You got that right,
you little son of a...
Hey, look,
I made a mistake.
Damn right you
made a mistake!
Kill him!
I'm gonna tear
your ass up!
That's right.
You keep running, sucker!
And you tell
that realty company
that I ain't selling!
You hear?
We ain't gonna
be terrorized!
This has gotta
be the wrong year.
1985?
It can't be.
Drop it.
So you're the son of a bitch
who's been stealing my newspapers.
Mr. Strickland.
Mr. Strickland. It's
me, sir. It's Marty.
Who?
It's Marty McFly.
Marty McFly.
Don't you know me, sir?
From school, sir.
I've never seen you
before in my life,
but you look to
me like a slacker.
Yeah, that's right. That's
right. I am a slacker.
Don't you remember? You
gave me detention last week.
Last week? The school
burned down six years ago.
Now, you got
exactly three seconds
to get off my porch
with your nuts intact.
One.
Please, Mr. Strickland,
I just want to know what
the hell's going on here.
Two.
Hey, Strickland!
Yeah!
Eat lead, slackers!
Watch where you're going,
crazy drunk pedestrian.
Red.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the Biff Tannen Museum.
Dedicated to Hill Valley's
number one citizen
and America's
greatest living folk hero,
the one and only
Biff Tannen.
Of course, we've all heard
the legend, but who is the man?
Inside, you will learn
how Biff Tannen became
one of the richest
and most powerful men
in America.
Learn the amazing history
of the Tannen family,
starting with his great-grandfather,
Buford "Mad Dog" Tannen,
fastest gun in the West.
See Biff's
humble beginnings
and how a trip
to the racetrack
on his 21 st birthday made
him a millionaire overnight.
Share in the excitement
of a fabulous winning streak
that earned him the nickname
"The Luckiest Man on Earth. "
Learn how Biff parlayed
that lucky winning streak
into the vast empire
called Biffco.
Discover how in 1979, Biff successfully
lobbied to legalize gambling
and turned Hill Valley's
dilapidated courthouse
into a beautiful
casino hotel.
I just want to say one
thing. God bless America!
Meet the women
who shared in his passion
as he searched
for true love,
and relive
Biff's happiest moment
as, in 1973, he realized
his life-long romantic dream
by marrying his high school
sweetheart, Lorraine Baines McFly.
How's it feel,
Mr. Tannen?
Third time's
the charm.
No! No!
Hey, you're coming
with us upstairs.
Let me go.
Look, sonny, we can do this
the easy way or the hard way.
The easy way.
Mom? Mom, is that you?
Just relax, Marty.
You've been asleep
for almost two hours.
I had a horrible nightmare.
It was terrible.
Well, you're safe
and sound now,
back on the good
old 27th floor.
Twenty-seventh floor!
Mom?
Mom, that can't be you.
Well, yes, it's me,
Marty. Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm fine. It's just
that you're so... You're so
big.
Oh. Everything's gonna be
fine, Marty. Are you hungry?
I can call room service.
Room service?
Lorraine!
Oh, my God.
It's your father.
My father?
You're supposed to be in Switzerland,
you little son of a bitch!
My father!
Did you get kicked out
of another boarding school?
Damn it, Lorraine. Do you know
how much perfectly good dough
I've blown on this
no-good kid of yours, huh?
On all three of them?
What the hell do you
care? We can afford it.
The least we can do
with all that money
is provide a better life
for our children.
Hold on one second.
Let's get this straight.
Marty is your kid, not mine.
And all the money
in the world
wouldn't do jack shit
for that lazy bum.
Stop it, Biff.
Just stop it.
Look at him. He's a butthead,
just like his old man was.
Don't you dare speak
that way about George.
You're not even
half the man he was.
You son of a bitch!
Hey.
Always
the little hothead, huh?
You wanna
take a poke at me?
Damn it, Biff.
That's it. I'm leaving.
So go ahead. But think
about this, Lorraine!
Who's gonna pay for
all your clothes, huh?
And your jewelry
and your liquor?
Who's gonna pay for your
cosmetic surgery, Lorraine?
You were the one who wanted
me to get these things.
If you want them back,
you can have them.
Look, Lorraine.
You walk out that door,
and I won't only cut off
you. I'll cut off your kids.
You wouldn't.
Wouldn't I?
First your daughter,
Linda.
I'll cancel all
her credit cards.
She can settle her debts
with the bank all by herself.
Your idiot son, Dave. I'll
get his probation revoked.
And as for Marty.
Well, maybe you'd like to have
all three of your kids behind bars,
just like
your brother Joey.
One big, happy,
jailbird family.
All right, Biff.
You win. I'll stay.
As for you, I'll be back up here
in an hour, so you better not be.
He was right,
and I was wrong.
Mom!
Mom,
what are you saying?
You're actually
defending him.
I had it coming.
He's my husband,
and he takes care
of all of us,
and he deserves
our respect.
Respect?
Your husband! How could
he be your husband?
How could you
leave Dad for him?
Leave Dad?
Marty, are you
feeling all right?
No. No, I'm not
feeling all right!
I don't understand one damn
thing that's going on around here,
and why nobody can give me
a simple, straight answer.
Oh, they must have hit you
over the head hard this time.
Mom, I just want
to know one thing.
Where's my father?
Where's George McFly?
Marty, George,
your father
is in the same place he's
been for the past 12 years.
Oak Park Cemetery.
No.
No! This can't
be happening!
"March 15, 1973."
No! Please, God, no!
No, please, God.
Please, God, no.
This can't be happening.
This can't be...
I'm afraid it is
happening, Marty. All of it.
Doc!
When I learned
about your father,
I figured
you'd come here.
Then you know
what happened to him?
Do you know what
happened March 15, 1973?
Yes, Marty. I know.
I went
to the public library
to try to make sense
out of all the madness.
The place was
boarded up, shut down,
so I broke in and
borrowed some newspapers.
I don't get it, Doc.
I mean, how can all
this be happening?
It's like we're in
hell or something.
No, it's Hill Valley. Although, I
can't imagine hell being much worse.
Oh, Einie.
I'm sorry, boy.
The lab is an awful,
awful, awful, awful mess.
Attaboy.
Obviously, the time
continuum has been disrupted,
creating this new
temporal event sequence
resulting in this
alternate reality.
English, Doc.
Here, here, here.
Let me illustrate.
Imagine that this line
represents time.
Here's the present, 1985,
the future and the past.
Prior to this point in
time, somewhere in the past,
the timeline skewed
into this tangent
creating
an alternate 1985.
Alternate to you,
me and Einstein,
but reality for
everyone else.
Recognize this?
It's the bag
the sports book came in.
I know, because the
receipt was still inside.
I found them in the time
machine along with this.
It's the top
of Biff's cane.
I mean,
Old Biff from the future.
Correct. It was
in the time machine
because Biff was in the time
machine with the sports almanac.
Holy shit.
You see, while we were in the future,
Biff got
the sports book,
stole the time machine,
went back in time,
and gave the book to himself
at some point in the past.
Look. It says right here
that Biff made
his first million
betting on a horse race
in 1958.
He wasn't just lucky.
He knew because he had all the
race results in the sports almanac.
That's how he made
his entire fortune.
Look at his pocket
with a magnifying glass.
The almanac.
Son of a bitch
stole my idea.
He must have been
listening when I...
It's my fault. The
whole thing is my fault.
If I hadn't bought
that damn book,
none of this would
have ever happened.
Well, it's all
in the past.
You mean the future?
Whatever.
It demonstrates precisely
how time travel
can be misused
and why the time machine
must be destroyed
after we straighten
all of this out.
Right. So we go
back to the future,
and we stop Biff from
stealing the time machine.
We can't,
because if we travel
into the future from
this point in time,
it will be the future
of this reality,
in which Biff is
corrupt and powerful
and married
to your mother
and in which this
has happened to me.
No. Our only chance to repair
the present is in the past
at the point where the timeline
skewed into this tangent.
In order to put the universe
back as we remember it
and get back
to our reality,
we have to find
out the exact date
and the specific
circumstances
of how, where
and when Young Biff
got his hands on
that sports almanac.
I'll ask him.
Bulletproof vest! Great
flick! Great frigging flick!
The guy is brilliant.
Hey, what the hell's
going...
Hey! What the hell
are you doing in here?
Party's over, Biff.
Sorry, ladies.
How did you get past
my security downstairs?
There's a little matter
we need to talk about.
Yeah. Money, right?
Well, forget it.
No. Not money.
Gray's Sports Almanac.
You heard him, girls.
Party's over.
Start talking, kid. What
else you know about that book?
First, you tell me
how you got it.
How, where and when.
All right.
Take a seat.
Sit down!
November 12, 1955.
That was when.
November 12, 1955. That
was the date I went back...
That was the date of the famous
Hill Valley lightning storm.
You know your history.
Very good.
I'll never forget
that Saturday.
I'd just picked
my car up from the shop,
'cause I'd rolled it in a
drag race a few days earlier.
I thought you crashed
into a manure truck.
How do you know
about that?
My father told me
about it.
Your father?
Before he died.
Yeah. Right.
So there I was,
minding my own business.
This crazy old codger
with a cane shows up.
He says he's my
distant relative.
I don't see
any resemblance.
So he says, "How would
you like to be rich?"
So I said, "Sure. "
So he lays
this book on me.
He says this book
will tell me the outcome
of every sporting event
till the end of the century.
All I have to do is bet on the
winner, and I'll never lose.
So I said,
"What's the catch?"
He says, "No catch.
Just keep it a secret. "
After that,
he disappeared.
I never saw him again.
Oh, and he told me
one more thing.
He said, "Someday a
crazy, wild-eyed scientist,
"or a kid may show up
asking about that book.
"And if that
ever happens... "
Funny. I never
thought it would be you.
Yeah, well, Biff, you're
forgetting one thing.
What the hell is that?
You're dead,
you little son of a bitch!
Hey, there he is!
Hey, hey!
Oh, yeah!
Go ahead, kid. Jump.
A suicide will
be nice and neat.
What if I don't?
Lead poisoning.
What about
the police, Biff?
They're gonna match up
the bullet with that gun.
Kid, I own the police.
Besides,
they couldn't match up
the bullet that
killed your old man.
You son of a...
I suppose it's
poetic justice.
Two McFlys
with the same gun.
Idiot.
What the hell?
Nice shot, Doc!
You're not
gonna believe this.
We gotta
go back to 1955.
I don't believe it.
That's right, Doc.
November 12, 1955.
Unbelievable that Old Biff could've
chosen that particular date.
It could mean that
that point in time
inherently contains some
sort of cosmic significance,
almost as if it were
the temporal junction point
for the entire
space-time continuum.
On the other hand, it could
just be an amazing coincidence.
Damn!
Got to fix that thing.
All right.
Time circuits on.
What do you mean,
time circuits on?
Doc, we're not
going back now.
Yep.
Doc, what about Jennifer?
What about Einstein?
We can't just
leave them here.
Don't worry, Marty. Assuming
we succeed in our mission,
this alternate 1985 will be
changed back into the real 1985,
instantaneously transforming
around Jennifer and Einie.
Jennifer and Einie
will be fine,
and they will have absolutely
no memory of this horrible place.
Doc.
What if we don't succeed?
We must succeed.
This is heavy, Doc. I mean, it's
like I was just here yesterday.
You were here yesterday,
Marty. You were.
Amazing, isn't it?
All right, sunrise should
be in about 22 minutes.
You go into town. Track
down Young Biff and tail him.
Sometime today,
Old Biff will show up
to give Young Biff
the almanac.
Above all you, must not
interfere with that event.
We must let Old Biff believe he's
succeeded, so that he'll leave 1955
and bring the DeLorean
back to the future.
Right.
Once Old Biff is gone, grab the
almanac any way that you can.
Remember, both of our
futures depend on this.
You don't have to
remind me of that, Doc.
Here's some binoculars and a
walkie-talkie so we can keep in contact.
I'll stay here and try to repair
the short in the time circuit.
That way, we don't risk anyone
else stealing the time machine,
and I won't risk accidentally
running into my other self.
Other self?
Yes. There are now
two of me here,
and there are
two of you here.
The other me is the Dr.
Emmett Brown from 1955,
the younger me that helps the
other you get back to 1985.
Remember the lightning bolt
at the clock tower?
Yeah. That event doesn't
happen until tonight,
so you must be very careful
not to run into your other self.
Let me give you
some money.
I have to be prepared for
all monetary possibilities.
Get yourself
some '50s clothes.
Check, Doc.
Something inconspicuous.
Doc. Come in, Doc.
This is Marty. Over.
Roger, Marty. This is Doc.
Are you there?
Yeah, Doc.
I'm at the address.
It's the only Tannen
in the book,
but I don't think
this is Biff's house.
It looks like some
old lady lives here.
Biff!
Yeah.
Where are you
going, Biff?
I'm going to get
my car, Grandma.
When are you
coming back?
My feet hurt, and I want
you to rub my toes some more.
Shut up,
you old bag.
Give us
our ball back.
What ball?
That ball!
What ball are
you talking about?
Give us our ball!
What ball?
Biff!
Is this your ball?
Yeah!
Is it your ball?
You want it back?
Yeah.
Go get it.
Doc, it is Biff's house.
I'm on him. Over.
Hey.
Looking good, Terry.
Hey, Biff, she's all
fixed up just like new,
but I couldn't
get her started.
You got some kind of
kill switch on this thing?
No, you just gotta
have the right touch.
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Yeah, the bill
comes to $302.57.
300 bucks?
300 bucks for
a couple of dents?
No, hey,
that's bullshit, Terry.
No, Biff,
it was horse shit.
The whole car
was full of it.
We had to pay Old Man Jones
80 bucks to haul it away.
Old Man Jones
probably resold it, too.
Now I ought to get
something for that.
You want
something for it?
We'll go inside. You
can call Old Man Jones.
If he wants to
give you a refund...
It's 300 bucks, Terry.
If I catch the guy that caused
this, I'll break his neck.
The manure.
I remember that.
Four cans of Valvoline
is fair, Biff.
Four cans
for a $300 job?
I couldn't even
have lunch in the shop.
Makes me nauseous. I
should get a case of oil
out of you for a 300 buck
job. You've been inside.
It smells worse than the
bathroom at a gas station.
You robbed me again,
Terry. Yeah, yeah.
The smell's never
gonna go away, Biff.
Never gonna go away.
Last time I do you a favor.
Last time. Thanks a lot.
Let me see.
It's perfect,
Lorraine.
Oh, look at it!
You're going to
look so good!
You're going
to look...
Well, lookey
what we have here.
Hey, nice dress,
Lorraine.
Although, I think you'd look
better wearing nothing at all.
Biff, why don't you take a
long walk off a short pier?
Hey, listen, Lorraine.
There's that dance at
school tonight, right.
Now that
my car's all fixed,
I figure
I'd cut you a break
and give you
the honor of going
with the best-looking
guy in school.
Yeah, well, I'm busy.
Yeah, doing what?
Washing my hair.
That's about as funny as a
screen door on a battleship.
Screen door on
a submarine, you dork.
Look, Biff, somebody already
asked me to the dance.
Who? That bug
George McFly?
I'm going with
Calvin Klein, okay?
Calvin Klein?
No, it's not okay.
You're going
with me, understand?
Get your cooties
off me!
When are you gonna get it through
your thick skull, Lorraine?
You're my girl.
Biff Tannen,
I wouldn't be your girl
even if you had
a million dollars!
Yes, you will! It's
you and me, Lorraine.
Watch it!
It's meant to be.
I'm going to marry
you someday, Lorraine.
Someday you'll
be my wife!
You always did
have a way with women.
Get the hell out
of my car, old man.
You want to marry
that girl, Biff?
I can help
make it happen.
Oh, yeah? Who are you,
Miss Lonely-Hearts?
Just get in the car,
butthead.
Who are you calling
butthead, butthead?
How do you know
how to do that?
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Just get in the car, Tannen.
Today's your lucky day.
Hey! Hey! Hey, watch where
you're driving, old man.
If you dent this car,
I'll kill you.
This cost me
300 bucks!
Would you shut up
about the car?
Hey, and another thing. How
do you know where I live?
Let's just say
we're related, Biff.
And that being the case, I
got a little present for you.
Something that'll
make you rich.
You want to be rich,
don't you?
Oh, yeah. Sure. Right.
That's rich.
You're going
to make me rich?
You see this book? This
book tells the future.
Tells the results of
every major sports event
till the end
of the century.
Football, baseball,
horse races, boxing.
The information in here is worth
millions, and I'm giving it to you.
Well, that's very nice.
Thank you very much.
Now, why don't you make like
a tree and get out of here?
It's leave, you idiot.
Make like a tree and leave.
You sound like a damn fool
when you say it wrong.
All right, then, leave and
take your book with you.
Don't you get it? You could
make a fortune with this book.
Let me show you.
UCLA trails 17-16.
It's 4th and 11 with only
18 seconds left of this game.
I'd say it's
all over for UCLA.
Bet you a million bucks
UCLA wins it 19-17.
What are you,
deaf, old man?
He just said it was over.
You lost.
Oh, yeah?
Here comes Decker
with the kick.
It's up.
It looks good, folks!
It looks very good. Field
goal! UCLA wins 19-17.
Listen to that Coliseum
crowd go wild. Jim Decker...
All right, pops.
What's the gag?
How did you know what
the score was gonna be?
I told you.
It's in this book.
All you gotta do is bet on the
winner, and you'll never lose.
All right.
I'll take a look at it.
You damn fool!
Never, never leave
this book laying around.
Don't you have a safe?
No, you don't have a safe.
Get a safe.
Keep it locked up.
And until then, keep
it on you like this.
Hey, what are you doing?
And don't tell anybody about it, either.
And there's
one more thing.
One day, a kid or a
crazy, wild-eyed old man
who claims to
be a scientist
is going to come around
asking about this...
If that ever happens...
I'm trapped. Doc.
Doc, come in, Doc.
Marty, what's the report?
Biff's gone.
He's got the book.
The old man's gone, too.
I'm locked in Biff's garage.
You gotta fly
the DeLorean over here
and get me
the hell out of here.
The address is
1809 Mason Street.
I can't take the DeLorean
out in the daylight,
but don't worry, Marty.
Somehow I'll get over there.
Doc, wait a minute.
Doc. Hey, Doc. Doc.
Perfect.
I told you, Grandma.
I'm going to the dance.
When you coming home?
The dance.
I'll get home
when I get home.
Don't forget to turn
off the garage light.
Marty. Marty!
Marty.
Marty, Marty. Damn!
Where is that kid?
Doc. Doc, come in.
Come in, Doc.
Marty! Marty, come in.
Doc.
Marty.
Oh, my...
Great Scott.
Oh, my God.
Doc, Doc, come in.
Marty,
what happened to you?
I went to Biff's house,
and you weren't there.
You must have
just missed me.
I'm in the back
of Biff's car.
He's on his way to the
Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
Marty, listen, we may have
to abort this entire plan.
It's getting
much too dangerous.
Don't worry. The book
is on Biff's dashboard.
I'll grab it as soon
as we get to the school.
Marty, you must
be extremely careful
not to run into
your other self.
My other self?
Yes.
Remember, your mother is at that
exact same dance with you. Yeah.
Right. This could
get heavy, Doc.
Heavy, heavy.
Marty, whatever happens, you must
not let your other self see you!
The consequences
could be disastrous.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, you with the hat.
Who, me?
Yes.
Be a pal and hand me a five-eighths
inch wrench out of that toolbox.
Five-eighths?
Don't you mean
three-quarters?
Why, you're right.
I presume you're conducting
some sort of weather experiment.
That's right.
How did you know that?
I happen to have had a little
experience in this area.
Yes, well, I'm hoping to
see some lightning tonight.
Although, the weatherman says
there's not gonna be any rain.
There's going to be
plenty of rain, all right.
Wind, thunder,
lightning.
It's gonna be one
hell of a storm.
Well, thanks.
Nice talking to you.
Maybe we'll bump into each other
some time again in the future.
Or in the past.
Doc, Doc! Come in!
Where's that punk
Calvin Klein, anyway?
How am I
supposed to know, Biff?
I ain't his secretary.
Well, go find him. He caused
300 bucks damage to my car,
and I owe him a knuckle
sandwich. Get going!
Drink up, Biff.
Yeah, thanks.
Ain't you coming?
I'm reading.
Well, well, well,
Mr. Tannen.
How nice
to see you here.
Why, Mr. Strickland,
it's nice to see you, sir.
Is that liquor
I smell, Tannen?
I wouldn't know.
I don't know what
liquor smells like,
'cause I'm too
young to drink it.
I see.
And what have we here?
Sports statistics, interesting
subject. Homework, Tannen?
No, it ain't homework,
'cause I ain't at home.
You've got a real
attitude problem.
You know that, Tannen?
Just watch it.
Because one day,
I'll have you
right where I want you
in detention.
Slacker!
Jesus,
you smoke, too?
Marty, you're beginning to
sound just like my mother.
Yeah, right.
When I have kids, I'm going to
let them do anything they want.
Anything at all.
Yeah, I'd like to
have that in writing.
Yeah, me, too.
Marty,
why are you so nervous?
Yes!
No!
"Oh L L?"
Doc! Doc!
Hey, you.
Doc, come in!
Marty, what's up?
Doc! I'm in trouble.
I blew it.
Where's the book?
Biff must still
have it with him.
All I got is
the damn cover.
And where's Biff?
You're asking for it.
I don't know.
Don't you have any
idea where he is?
No! I mean, he could
be anywhere by now.
Marty, the entire
future depends on you
finding Biff and
getting that book back!
I know.
I just don't know where...
Stop it!
Stop it, Biff. You'll
break his arm. Stop it!
Of course!
I gotta go.
I got one chance!
My old man is
about to deck Biff!
Yes!
Talk about dj vu.
Are you okay?
Okay, everybody,
let's back up now.
Let's back up. Let's
everybody just back up
and give him a little bit of room, okay.
A little bit of air.
It's okay.
I know CPR. I know CPR.
Hey.
What's CPR?
You!
He's fine.
Hey, did you
just take his wallet?
He just took
that guy's wallet.
Doc, success.
I got it.
Thank goodness.
Great, Marty.
As soon as I reload
the fusion generator,
I'll meet you on the roof
of the high school gym.
On the roof. 10-4.
Hey, it's him!
Hey, he's in disguise.
Guys, what's that?
Come on!
Let's get him!
Damn!
Earth angel
Please be mine
My darling dear
Love you for all time
I'm just a fool
A fool in love
with you
All right!
Let's do another one.
Where did he go?
He just came in here!
Something
that really cooks.
Look! How did he
get up on stage?
I don't know, but when he gets
down, we're gonna nail him.
How the hell did he
change his clothes so fast?
All right, it's an
oldie where I come from.
All right, guys, listen,
this is a blues riff in B.
Watch me for the changes,
and try and keep up, okay?
Doc. Doc, come in!
Marty, come in.
Listen, Biff's guys chased me into
the gym, and they're going to jump me.
Then get out of there!
No, Doc, not me.
The other me.
The one that's up on stage
playing Johnny B. Goode.
Great Scott!
Your other self will miss
the lightning bolt
at the clock tower,
you won't get back to the future,
and we'll have a major paradox!
Wait, wait, wait.
A paradox?
You mean one of those things
that can destroy the universe?
Precisely. Marty, you have to
stop those guys at all costs,
but without being seen by your
other self or your parents.
10-4.
What the hell?
Where is he?
Who?
Calvin Klein.
The guy with the hat,
where is he?
Oh. He went that way.
I think he took your wallet.
I think he took his wallet.
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
Go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
I guess you guys aren't
ready for that yet.
But your kids are
going to love it.
Hey, Doc, success.
Everything's cool.
Great. I'll be landing at the
school roof in about one minute.
I'll be there.
Lorraine.
Marty, that was
very interesting music.
I hope you don't mind,
but George asked if
he could take me home.
Great. Lorraine, I had
a feeling about you two.
I have a feeling, too.
Hey, butthead!
You think that stupid
disguise would get by me?
Let's have it out.
You and me, right now.
No, thanks.
What's the matter?
Where are you going?
Are you chicken?
That's it, isn't it?
Nothing but a little chicken.
Nobody
calls me chicken.
What the hell?
You steal my stuff?
And this one's
for my car!
Doc!
Doc! I blew it.
Biff nailed me.
He took the book.
He drove away
with it in his car.
It's my fault, Doc. I should
have got out of there sooner.
No time for that now.
Which way did he go?
East towards
the River Road Tunnel.
Get in!
Yes!
There he is, Doc!
Let's land on him.
We'll cripple his car.
Marty, he's in a '46 Ford.
We're a DeLorean.
He'd rip through us
like we were tin foil.
So what do we do?
I have a plan.
Repeating tonight's
earlier weather bulletin,
a severe thunderstorm is
heading for Hill Valley.
Serving Hill Valley
and all of Hill County,
you're tuned to KKHV,
the voice of Hill Valley.
Turning to
community calendar,
the Hill Valley
Women's Club bake sale
will be held
tomorrow afternoon
from 2:00 to 5:00 at the
community center on Forest Road.
For you sports fans
out there,
there was a lot of action
today in college football.
Here's what happened
to the top 10.
UCLA narrowly
defeated Washington 19-17.
Michigan State
crushed Minnesota 42-14.
Ohio State
beat Iowa 20-10.
Michigan
blanked Indiana 30-0.
Shit.
It was Notre Dame over
North Carolina, 27-7.
Son of a bitch.
Oklahoma ripped
Iowa State 52-0.
West Virginia lost
to Pittsburgh 26-7.
Texas A&M over Rice 20-10.
Maryland
defeated Clemson 25-12,
and it was Texas
Christian over Texas 47-20.
Repeating tonight's earlier
weather bulletin, a severe...
You again?
Give me that book.
Let it go!
Whoa!
Let go of the car!
That'll teach him.
Oh!
Go, Doc!
Hold on, Marty!
Shit!
Yes!
Manure!
I hate manure!
Doc, is everything
all right? Over.
10-4, Marty, but it's pretty
miserable flying weather.
Much too turbulent to make a
landing from this direction.
I'll have to circle around and
make a long approach from the south.
Have you got the book?
In my hand, Doc!
I got it in my hand!
Burn it!
Check!
Doc! Doc!
That newspaper changed.
Doc, my father's alive!
That means everything's
back to normal, right?
Mission accomplished.
That means Jennifer's okay
and Einie's okay, right?
That's right, Marty.
It's the ripple effect.
The future is back,
so let's go home.
Right. Let's get our
asses back to the...
Doc, Doc,
are you okay?
That was a close one, Marty.
I almost bought the farm.
Well, be careful. You don't
want to get struck by lightning.
Doc.
Doc?
Doc, come in, Doc.
Doc, do you read me?
Do you read me, Doc?
Come in. Doc.
Oh, no.
He's gone.
The doc's gone.
Mr. McFly!
Huh?
Is your name
Marty McFly?
Yeah.
I've got something for you.
A letter.
A letter for me?
That's impossible.
Who the hell are you?
Western Union.
Actually, a bunch of us at
the office were kind of hoping
maybe you could shed
some light on the subject.
See, we've had that envelope in our
possession for the past 70 years.
It was given to us with
the explicit instructions
that it be delivered to a
young man with your description
answering to the name of
Marty at this exact location
at this exact minute,
November 12, 1955.
We have a little bet
going as to whether
this Marty would
actually be here.
Looks like I lost.
Did you say 70 years?
Yeah, 70 years, 2 months,
12 days to be exact.
Here sign on line 6,
please.
Here you are.
It's from the doc!
"Dear Marty, if my
calculations are correct,
"you will receive this
letter immediately after
"you saw the DeLorean
struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you
that I'm alive and well.
"I've been living happily these
past eight months in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt... "
1885!
"September, 1885."
Wait, wait, kid! Wait a
minute. What's this all about?
He's alive!
The doc's alive!
He's in the Old West,
but he's alive.
Yeah, but, kid,
you all right?
Do you need any help?
There's only one man
who can help me.
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Doc! Doc!
What?
Okay, relax, Doc. It's
me. It's me! It's Marty.
No, it can't be. I just
sent you back to the future.
Yeah. No, I know.
You did send me
back to the future,
but I'm back.
I'm back
from the future.
Great Scott!
Doc! Doc. Doc.
Fantastic.
Hey, McFly.
Just try it, Tannen!
Come on, runt! You can
dance better than that!